<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>The Royal Liar</title>
 <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/"/>
 <updated>2015-05-12T12:06:25+00:00</updated>
 <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>The Liars</name>
   <email>rl@marymountrome.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Alya J.</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/alya-j"/>
   <updated>2015-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/alya-j</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name:&lt;/strong&gt; Alya J.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Nickname:&lt;/strong&gt; Ally&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Grade:&lt;/strong&gt; 11&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Nationality:&lt;/strong&gt; Kuwaiti, Mexican American&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Years at MMI:&lt;/strong&gt; Almost 2 years&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Life motto:&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t be peanut butter and jealous and just give me some tater tots, dude. Ps. You should blow on this friendship rock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Celebrity crush?&lt;/em&gt; Seth Rogan, Chris Evans and Aaron Taylor Johnson.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Most awkward thing that ever happened to you?&lt;/em&gt; Mistaking the sex of little children when consulting their parents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;If your life were a song, what would the title be?&lt;/em&gt; Whoops, I did it again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Something you couldn’t live without?&lt;/em&gt; Cheeeeeeeeeessseee!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Someone you couldn’t live without?&lt;/em&gt; My best friends and family.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best thing that happened in 2014?&lt;/em&gt; The 1975 and Ed Sheeran concert.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you could have one superpower what would it be?&lt;/em&gt; Telekinesis!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Favorite subject?&lt;/em&gt; Chemistry, and music, Duh!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The perfect vacation?&lt;/em&gt; Somewhere where there’s Takis and an endless amount of good indie music.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cats or dogs?&lt;/em&gt; None! Sugar gliders. They’re so much cuter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Favorite artist?&lt;/em&gt; Wow. Dude: Morrissey, Chick: Etta James.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best thing that happened this month?&lt;/em&gt; My family from the states got to visit and that was really nice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best thing that happened ever?&lt;/em&gt; Too many fun and PG 13 things that include watching cartoons and a life time supply of pesto, of course!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Facebook or Instagram?&lt;/em&gt; Neither, tumbler.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Favorite holiday?&lt;/em&gt; Christmas (Says the Muslim).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Biggest surprise you’ve ever had?&lt;/em&gt; When I found out my mom was preggers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you could pick one historical figure to have coffee with, whom would you pick?&lt;/em&gt; Beethoven or Brahms. They seem like interesting psychotic people.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best gift you ever received?&lt;/em&gt; My life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Favorite country you visited?&lt;/em&gt; Spain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Number one goal in life?&lt;/em&gt; Being actually happy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Movie you laughed the hardest through?&lt;/em&gt; A Medea’s Christmas and Napoleon Dynamite 22. Best thing about living in Rome? Food and people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you could switch places with someone for a day, who would it be?&lt;/em&gt; No one, I’m pretty content with myself  .&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dream job?&lt;/em&gt; Professional musician.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who should everyone be following right now?&lt;/em&gt; Jon Gomm he’s great and really underrated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Ms. Ferrarin</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/ms-ferrarin"/>
   <updated>2015-04-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/ms-ferrarin</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ms. Ferrarin has been the drama teacher here at Marymount for the past six years and has directed a total of twelve shows with the Marymount players, the after school drama club.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interview conducted and transcribed by Ramzi Shatara.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R: How do you decide what musical or play you’re going to choose to do?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
F: Well, usually we think about the talent that we have. We think about all the people who have done musicals in the high school in the past, and we think about people who might be good, because we have to have an idea that we could possibly cast it [the musical] because it would be no good thinking of a show and then realizing we don’t have this character or that character or any possibility for a character.  So we think about what we have and then we come up with a list of possibilities. But for this show it was a bit different because I was almost, I was bullied into it by, [laughs] by a few little devils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R: For anyone who doesn’t know how it all works, what can you say about the process of putting it all together as a director? Do you make lists for yourself?Draw up set designs? What does it mean to be prepared when you come to rehearsal?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
F: Okay, yea, everything. All of that. It’s basically one of the biggest undertakings that you can do really because you have to have a vision of how it’s going to end, so you have to have an idea of what it’s going to look like or what you want it to look like. You might not get there but you have to have an understanding of what that might be. And you have to be as organized as possible so that all of those steps get completed. So there’s lots of list making, there’s basically a list a day for different things. You have to come up with a rehearsal schedule before auditions so you know you have enough time, so you have to work backwards. That’s basically it. It’s working backwards. It’s thinking of what you want the final thing to be and then working backwards and trying to fit everything in. And most of the time you can’t fit everything in, so you have to cram it in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R: Are there lots of times when you just have to improvise?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
F: Absolutely, there are plenty of times when you just have to skip over things or scenes because there is just no time. Time is the biggest factor. You just hope and pray that people go off and learn what they need to learn, so it’s really great as a director to have a cast who bring stuff to rehearsal and come prepared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R: Is there any piece of advice that you always find yourself giving to your actors?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
F: I think...probably...well, for a musical, I suppose the biggest one would be energy. Always. And for people who don’t know what that means, It would be bringing a certain level of energy onto the stage. So even if you make a big mistake or you don’t know what you’re doing you have to do it with confidence...because it’s incredible and very real, the sharing of energy between the audience and the actors. Also probably secondly, would be to make sure the story is told, because if the actor doesn’t understand their his or her and the story, they’re not going to be able to effectively tell it. Because that’s what it is at the end of the day. It’s a story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R: And not to take to themselves too seriously [laughs]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
F: Don’t take yourself too seriously! Yeah! Because otherwise you’re going to hold yourself back and not reach your true potential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R: What would you tell someone who has never really tried being in a play before, but wants to try?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
F: I would probably tell them that it would be completely different to what they expect. You get what you put in, with everything in life, but definitely something like that. You can adapt being apart of a performance like this to what you want to do, so if you want to do something huge and throw yourself in then go for a main role, if you just want to try it then come along and do a backstage roll and see how it’s done and build up your confidence that way. The most important thing is to try and have fun and we try and have fun and [laughs] sometimes I make it hard because I do lose my temper but that’s because I know that people can do it better than they are doing. It’s hard work but I think if you ask anyone and I challenge anyone to ask any cast member, past or present, how he or she felt at the end, they’ll tell you that they loved it. Because there’s nothing that compares to the moment that the curtains close and there’s an eruption of sound, and it’s all the actors and crew just letting off steam that they’ve managed to do it. The arts are for everybody, and everybody owns the arts, so even if you’ve never tried it before, its never too late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R: You’ve done twelve plays now at Marymount&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
F: Have I? [laughs]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R: Yea, it’s twelve as of West Side Story, so from the ones that you’ve done which were the most challenging and which was the most rewarding?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
F: The most challenging was West Side Story without a doubt. It was challenging because it’s a huge musical and it’s a musical that lots of people already know and love so the audience was coming in with big expectations and we had to meet them. So I really feel as a director and teacher, I want everyone to do their best. I want to do my best. So you push yourself and everyone else to make it happen. It was also very difficult musically. The most rewarding was probably...maybe because it was so difficult was West Side Story. But also maybe -- The one that I felt that I stretched
myself most as a director and I stretched the actors who I was working with was probably Twelve Angry Men. It was something new that we hadn’t done before and nothing we have done since. That was a real ensemble piece and I really like ensemble pieces because it means everyone is working together; everyone was on stage the entire time...it was tough, but really good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R: Can you give us any hints about next year’s shows?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
F: Can I? No, [laughs] I honestly have no idea what the shows will be, we kind of have ideas floating around, but we can’t choose until we see that list of people who sign up. So all I’ll say is that if you’re interested, sign up.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Afterlife, Frankenstein, and Reanimation</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/the-afterlife-frankenstein-and-reanimation"/>
   <updated>2015-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/the-afterlife-frankenstein-and-reanimation</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The thought of life after death has been with us since the beginning of mankind. This dates back to the Neanderthals and every civilization since. The Egyptians, from approximately 3100 to 332 BC, believed that immortality could be achieved if Pharaohs were mummified, bringing items with them to take to the afterlife. The person’s heart would then be weighed of sins, and depending on whether or not there were any, they would pass on or be devoured by Ammit, a demon. The Greeks, dating back to 800-500 BC, believed the souls of the deceased would be judged by Hades, the god of the underworld, and based on their sins or goodness, would be sent to either the fields of punishment or of peacefulness and content. Similarly, the Vikings, around 800-1066 AD, surmised that warriors would spend their afterlives in Valhalla, sinners in Hel, and others in Fólkvangr, a massive meadow to be reunited with loved ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of these civilizations, however, thought of bringing the dead back to life. In the late Romantic era, Mary Wollstonecraft Shelley thought of what might happen if a person were to be reassembled and reanimated through galvanism in the first ever science fiction novel, &lt;em&gt;Frankenstein&lt;/em&gt;. The main character, Dr. Victor Frankenstein, is able to successfully put together a creature capable of love, despite (spoiler alert) resulting in the deaths of almost every character. Her work brought forward lots of criticism on the religious and moral aspects of reanimating the dead, and instilled fear in societies that had just begun to embrace electricity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flash forward to the present, where patients are revived through resuscitation (CPR), or preserved through cryopreservation (freezing organisms in the hopes of being revived in the future) in almost every modern hospital. Science has come a long way since the Greeks and the Egyptians, and we, at &lt;em&gt;the Royal Liar&lt;/em&gt;, can’t help but wonder how much further it’ll advance. Globally, life expectancy rates are increasing, but with this come over population and a strain on resources. All of these are important factors to keep in mind when considering manipulating the inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Formula 1 2015 Starts Off in Melbourne</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/formula-1-2015-starts-off-in-melbourne"/>
   <updated>2015-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/formula-1-2015-starts-off-in-melbourne</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After Lewis Hamilton’s win in Abu Dhabi four months ago which granted him his second drivers’ championship, Formula 1 fans were anxious to see the changes to teams and drivers as well as the rules, but most of all they were ready for the start of the new season. There were a couple of changes to the rules this year, primarily the introduction of the virtual safety car.  After the Japanese Grand Prix in October 2014 where Jules Bianchi had an almost fatal accident, from which he is still recovering from today, the Fédération Internationale de l’Automobile (FIA) have introduce the virtual safety car; which will mean that drivers will have to slow down in areas where there has been a crash. Other changes to rules include the loss of double points during the last race. The drivers are now limited to four engines for the whole season and radio communication with the boxes will be restricted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest change, though, has been in the makeup of the teams. The title favorites are both of Mercedes’ star drivers, Lewis Hamilton and Nico Rosberg. Then there will probably be an interesting battle for the third place between the two Williams (Valtteri Bottas and Felipe Massa) and Ferrari (Sebastian Vettel and Kimi Räikkönen) drivers. Now that it seems that Ferrari is becoming more of a competitor it is clear that Fernando Alonso’s decision to leave the team for McLaren was misguided. Like Dani Pedrosa, who although not a F1 driver but a motorcycle racer, has the same misfortune as Alonso because has won three third places and three second places in Moto GP but never first. Now that Alonso has left Ferrari for McLaren who he thought had a more competitive car, Ferrari is fighting for the third place while the only McLaren that finished came in last. But the most surprising thing in the 2015 line-up has to be the 17 year-old rookie Max Verstappen who races for the Toro Rosso team, the sister team of Red Bull.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the first race of the season, it can be described as an overall fiasco. First of all, there were multiple mechanical problems, resulting in just a 75% of cars turning up on the grid for the first race. Of these 15 cars 4 of them had to drop out meaning that only 55% of the cars actually finished. Clearly this is not the path to attract more viewers to the already declining viewership of the once great sport. As it stands there are basically only two drivers with a true possibility at winning the title, Hamilton and Rosberg from the Mercedes team. Hamilton came in 1&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;sup&gt; and Rosberg 2&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; at Melbourne. Alonso, who could potentially be a contender for the top, but most likely won’t be able to compete due to a concussion he suffered from in his crash in Barcelona during testing. Hopefully he will recover in time to attend the next race in Malaysia on March 29th so that the season can get a little bit more interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Opinions to Die For</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/opinions-to-die-for"/>
   <updated>2015-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/opinions-to-die-for</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On February 27th of this year, mere minutes before midnight, Russian politician Boris Nemtsov was gunned down on a bridge next to the Kremlin in central Moscow. The killers sped off in a white vehicle, but 5 were apprehended a little over a week after the assassination, and a sixth blew himself up with a grenade before he could be arrested. All the men are ethnic Chechens, but an extremist Islamist motive behind the attack has been strongly refuted. Zaur Dadayev has been identified as the brain behind the operation, but Dadayev himself claimed that he was tortured and that the police forced him to confess, and has subsequently retracted both his claims of torture and confession. International media reporting on the homicide and its ensuing investigation always includes “Putin’s opponent” along with Nemtsov’s name in the segment or article title, blatantly implying Putin was partially or directly responsible for Boris Nemtsov’s unfortunate end. The victim’s own daughter recently proclaimed her father was  “the most powerful leader of the opposition in Russia” and a “fighter”. Indeed, the media has transformed Nemtsov into a sort of martyr-a rebel leader, someone who stood up to the infamous Putin, and a man who had opinions that he was ready to die for. These days, the western media regards anybody who is in opposition to Putin favorably. At the time of his death, Boris Nemtsov was working on a report that would prove the presence of the Russian military in Eastern Ukraine (even though such assertions have been vehemently denied). Less than three weeks before his assassination, Nemtsov admitted in an interview that he was afraid for his life. It seems like an open-and-shut case; Putin ordered the murder of his feared opponent Boris Nemtsov, and is now trying to cover it up. Except Putin never feared or had any reason to fear Boris Nemtsov, and the whole situation is much more complicated than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the early 90’s, Boris Nemtsov was a young, bureaucrat from a small, provincial Russian town. He attracted the attention of Boris Yeltsin, the first president of the Russian Federation, and immediately entered his inner circle. Boris Yeltsin chose his favorites not based on their political capabilities or achievements, but based on personal preference, and it wasn’t very hard to understand why he had picked the charismatic and good-natured Nemtsov.  For this reason, it’s not too farfetched to say that Boris Nemtsov was directly involved in ruling and exploiting the crumbling remains of the Soviet empire. Tons of people in Yeltsin’s inncer circle, along with Nemtsov and Yeltsin’s daughter amassed billions. Eventually, Yeltsin would publicly announce “I’m tired, I’m leaving.” and do everything in his power to pass on his position to Putin, who in return issued a decree that would protect Yeltsin and his family from any corruption charges. Once president, Putin swapped Yeltsin’s inner circle with his own cronies, which Boris Nemtsov was no longer a part of. Vladimir Putin followed in his predecessor’s footsteps and accumulated his own fortune, and Boris Nemtsov was left out and bitterly started his opposition campaign. Due to the fact Boris Nemtsov was an ordinary politician with no particular talent, most of his “opposition” took place in the provincial towns that he was from-far from Moscow, and Putin. In the past few years, Boris Nemtsov’s popularity level was extremely low, and many people did not know who he was. He lived a comfortable life with his young, model Ukranian girlfriend, and his murder left many wondering around the circumstances surrounding his death. Even though he was a forgotten political figure, his passing was a huge tragedy for the Russian people. The Russian media has a spectrum of theories and responses ranging from “Putin was responsible!” on the revolutionary TV channel “Rain” to theories that the West orchestrated the killing and make Putin the scapegoat. However, recently released information about Nemtsov may explain why he was even a murder target. Boris Nemtsov secretly cooperated with the United States, and assisted them in creating a list of Russian oligarchs and government officials to sanction. It is highly possible that one of the sanctioned victims had a vendetta against him, and decided to pursue it in the most lethal way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that Nemtsov should have been judged over 20 years ago when he was in power and the right hand of president Yeltsin, and billions of dollars poured into Western banks. Though his death is undoubtedly devastating, Nemtsov should not be regarded as a “rebel hero”. His foray into becoming an oppositioner was motivated by his exclusion from the inner circle that had access to the financial resources of the country, and constantly stole from the people of Russia. He didn’t die for his opinions, he died because he betrayed the members of his “gang”.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Determined Royals Look on to Jubilant Season Finale</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/determined-royals-look-on-to-jubilant-season-finale"/>
   <updated>2015-04-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/determined-royals-look-on-to-jubilant-season-finale</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The first two games against Naples and Sigonella have already set a clear picture in the minds of those who have followed the DODDS tournament: the Royals Boys Soccer team is completely dominant in Italy. A 3-1 away win against perhaps the second strongest team, Naples, and an 8-0 annihilation of Sigonella are indicative of this. The team is perhaps the most united in the league, with each player giving 110% every time they take to the field and really playing for each other. The Royals are an example to be followed by all, in fact, even Italian Serie A giants AS Roma who are struggling and have been accused of being mercenaries who care for nothing but money. Rest assured that the Royals have something to play for each time they take the field, and justly rewarded the fans who flooded the stand to see them play Sigonella.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shall we take a brief look at the technical aspects that have enabled them to win thus far? First of all, there is the coach, Roberto Rossi, to thank. He is a man with a winning mentality, who advocates for high intensity and commitment whenever the team takes to the field, and knows how to maintain a balance of hard work and enjoyment. Secondly there is the defense, with Andrea Pregoni proving to be a worthy replacement of his brother alongside Giovanni Acampora. Rest assured that trying to get past these two is like running through a brick wall. The cement of this wall can be seen as Giammaria Montella, the goalkeeper who guides the team from his position. Up front there has been no shortage of goals, created by the industrious midfield and finished by a clinical attack led by the man of the moment: Diego Piorico. 6 out of the 11 goals are his, and the Royals will look to him to provide for them in the crucial games. In short, this is a team who starts strong and finishes stronger, and most importantly plays as a team with each player helping the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The remaining matches in Italy seem straightforward for the Royals, with away trips to Florence and Aviano, but watch out for the long awaited “derby” with AOSR. It is a game the Royals will go into brimming with confidence and enthusiasm, eager to bring home a win after having been held to a 2-2 draw last year. After that comes the European Championship with the Royals hoping to retain their 3 consecutive titles in Kaiserslautern. As they say in Italy, in fact: “Non c’è due senza tre e il quattro vien’ da sé”. This is a proverb the Royals will hope to fulfill, and crown the final year of the seniors in the squad, some of the which will unfortunately be unavailable due to exams.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Lotanna M.</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/lotanna-m"/>
   <updated>2015-04-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/lotanna-m</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name:&lt;/strong&gt; Lotanna M.
&lt;strong&gt;Nickname:&lt;/strong&gt; Lolo/Làlo/Lorenzo/Samuel
&lt;strong&gt;Grade:&lt;/strong&gt; 11
&lt;strong&gt;Nationality:&lt;/strong&gt; Nigerian
&lt;strong&gt;Years at MMI:&lt;/strong&gt; 5
&lt;strong&gt;Life motto:&lt;/strong&gt; If I don’t do it first, I want to do it better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Celebrity crush?&lt;/em&gt; Scarlett Johansson.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Most awkward thing that ever happened to you?&lt;/em&gt; Seeing Germano in the shower.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pepsi or coke?&lt;/em&gt; Coke.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Something you couldn’t live without?&lt;/em&gt; Soccer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Someone you couldn’t live without?&lt;/em&gt; My mother.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Number one goal in life?&lt;/em&gt; To do things I can’t imagine now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you could have one superpower, what would it be?&lt;/em&gt; Immortality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Favorite subject?&lt;/em&gt; Biology because Mr. Zinzi is my best friend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best money you ever spent?&lt;/em&gt; Buying a printer for school.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;3 things you’d take to a deserted island?&lt;/em&gt; Phone, ball, food.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best thing that happened in 2014?&lt;/em&gt; Become soccer champions for the 4th time in a row.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best thing that happened this month?&lt;/em&gt; Beating Sigonella by 8 goals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best thing that happened ever?&lt;/em&gt; Having brothers around me all the time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Movie you laughed the hardest through?&lt;/em&gt; The Dictator and Horrible Bosses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Favorite holiday?&lt;/em&gt; Christmas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Biggest surprise you’ve ever had?&lt;/em&gt; Trip to Budapest to see my big brother.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you could pick one historical figure to have coffee with, whom would you pick?&lt;/em&gt; Francesco Totti because he’s Francesco Totti.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Favorite country you visited?&lt;/em&gt; Colombia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Country you want to visit?&lt;/em&gt; Japan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Favorite artist?&lt;/em&gt; Kanye West.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cats or dogs?&lt;/em&gt; Dogs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best thing about living in Rome?&lt;/em&gt; AS Roma.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best gift you ever received?&lt;/em&gt; PS3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Weirdest word in the English language?&lt;/em&gt; Fella.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;If your life were a song, what would the title be?&lt;/em&gt; All I Do is Win.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>West Side Story: The Review</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/west-side-story-the-review"/>
   <updated>2015-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/west-side-story-the-review</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I went to see the Marymount Players preform the iconic American musical: &lt;em&gt;West Side Story&lt;/em&gt;, directed by Gina Ferrarin, on the opening night, and I have to say that overall I was impressed.  The story is inspired by William Shakespeare’s tragedy &lt;em&gt;Romeo and Juliet&lt;/em&gt;; however it is set in New York’s Upper West Side in the 1950’s. The musical explores the rivalry between the Jets, an American gang, and the Sharks, who are from Puerto Rico, taunted by the Jets for their ethnicity. The rivalry between the two gangs ends when former Jet leader, Tony (Ramzi Shatara) falls in love with the leader of the Sharks, Bernardo’s (Michele Musilli) sister, Maria (Azzurra Moores). Of course, being based on Shakespeare’s tragedy, the rivalry between the two gangs will only end with the tragic end of the “star-crossed lovers’” love story, resulting in Tony’s death and Maria’s desperation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The relationship between the entire cast was comfertable and realistic, resulting in a successful suspension of disbelief for the audience. The female characters, Maria and her best friend/brother’s girlfriend, Anita (Alya Juahili), had great chemistry on stage and sang harmoniously together. Moores portayed a naive and quite fanciful Maria, perfectly reflecting the démodé character. Alya played a sassy and hopeful Anita, which presented a nice contrast to Maria, enhancing their relationship even more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The male protagonists Tony, his best friend Riff (Giulio Starace) and Bernardo (Musilli) also interpreted their roles very well. Like Moores, Shatara offered a naive and sensitive protagonist who was juxtaposed to every other male character in the play, making him stand out from the cast. Starace also interpreted the role of the Jets’ leader well and skillfully developed the character of an American stud, which turned out to be softer than what the audience expected. Musilli also played a charismatic and credible Bernardo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the cast was also very good: the Jets hilarious and modern in comparison to the rest of the play, and the Shark girls charmingly portrayed the expectations and dreams of Puerto Rican girls living in America in the 1950’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The music of the play was by far the best element of the performance. The cherubic voice of Azzurra Moores in the last song gave me chills, and the performance of Azzura Moores, Costanza Filì, Roberta Sidotti and Elle Pinkerton in “I Feel Pretty” was incredibly enjoyable. Shatara and Moores’ duet in “Tonight” was also exceptional; however, due to technical problems with the microphones, sometimes one of the two voices was less audible. The best song was definitely “America” with Alya’s amazing voice leading the Sharks in a fun and well-performed act. The band led by Rocco Sbardella accompanied the actors superbly, enhancing the lyrics, voices and instrumental elements of the band. Mr. Sbardella did a great job conducting and teaching the songs to the actors and band alike, delivering a professional performance. The only criticism I have is that sometimes the band was too loud relative to the actors’ voices.
The directing by Ms. Ferrarin was impeccable as always, producing a school production that can definitely compete with some semi-professional companies in Italy. The exits, entrances, changes of scenery, lighting, blocking, and preparation of the actors were evidently a success. A fine example of this was the love scene between Maria and Tony, which was conducted with elegance and refined taste, enhancing their sentiment of true love that is central to the entire play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulations and well done to all!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Terminator T-1000 Prototype is Here</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/terminator-t-1000-prototype-is-here"/>
   <updated>2015-04-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/terminator-t-1000-prototype-is-here</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The T-1000 is a terrifying, shape-shifting liquid-metal robot from &lt;em&gt;Terminator 2&lt;/em&gt;. It is capable of transforming into anything, and it can pass through any small opening. This is one of those science fiction ideas, that seems impossible and made-up. But as we know, science-fiction has the potential to become real in the future. It turns out that this is the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This amazing discovery was made by a group of scientists in Tsinghua University in Beijing, China. They took a drop of gallium, which is liquid just under 30ºC, added some indium and tin, and placed it in sodium hydroxide, a liquid similar to salt water. Then, they dropped a flake of aluminum on the liquid-metal droplet. It immediately began to bubble, and started spinning really fast — so fast that it started moving on its own. So they thought, where can we use this? Well, it turns out that there are two main usages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is transportation. Because the metal is a liquid, it can bend and adjust to the path that it&amp;#39;s travelling in. By path, I mean like pipes. These droplets can move through twisted, thin pipes with ease. This can be useful when we want to transport things to places with hard access. We can create a larger droplet that can carry supplies inside, and they will be able to reach these places by morphing themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second is pumping. If we keep the droplet in place, it will keep spinning in place — the liquid around it will move instead of the droplet. This means that we can create smaller circuits without the need for a huge pump. We just need to drop one of these droplets inside! For example, we could make a cooling device without the need for a power supply. We just add the droplet, feed it with aluminum, and it works automatically!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also succeeded in making shapes with this droplet. We apply a little current, and depending on the current, the droplet will change shape. As long as the current&amp;#39;s there, the shape remains. The scientists made a tree-like shape, but it wasn&amp;#39;t that precise because they didn&amp;#39;t know how to handle it properly. If we find out the proper way to do this, we could make it look like a tree, a cloud, or anything we imagine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just the entry step of making a T-1000. We can&amp;#39;t really call it prototype. However, as we keep investigating, we might really be able to make robots that can change shape on the fly. We just need to know how this works. That means, there is still a whole lot of potential. Will we be able to actually create a T-1000? I believe, some day, yes.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Fake Brat: Part V</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/fake-brat-part-v"/>
   <updated>2015-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/fake-brat-part-v</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;“Jacobe Moorse and Cassandra Moorse instantly dead in a car accident seconds after their exit from the Royal Hotel.” The reporter’s voice played like a broken record in my head, as though it was taunting me. It couldn’t be real; none of this was real. Death couldn’t just tear my parents away from me. There was just so much we still had to figure out, so much we still needed to fix. My father still had to tell my mother he was cheating on her. My mother still had to learn what was going on in my life. We still had to have at least a moment where we could be an actual family. See, they can’t be gone.  There is just too much we still need to do. Too much we need to tell each other that I have tell them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kneeled; the dust of the old apartment suffocated me as I shivered. The room was still. All I could hear was of the sound my heart beating too fast in my ears mixed with someone’s thick laugh echoing along the walls of the room. I watched the television hesitantly, as it broadcasted footage from the scene. The limousine I was in with them only hours ago: destroyed, crushed and squashed in the middle of an intersection. A truck lay on its side a few meters away.  Red and blue lights reflected off the shattered pieces of glass on the road. Three human size black bags lay on the dull dark road next to an ambulance. The person’s laugh continued to reverberate through the lifeless room, the sound slowly getting louder and closer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A soft hand abruptly moved a strand of hair away from my face. My eyes flickered as I recognized the hand as Katelyn. She was so close that I could detect the small strands of brown in her eyes encircled by her eyelashes that were painted on with a thick layer of mascara. Her face filled with millions of emotions and yet I couldn’t feel anything. Physically my body felt dull and jaded, but mentally I felt like a stranger to emotions, and analyzing my surroundings became all of the sudden easier, as if my feelings were a fog hiding me from the clearer details. “Sweetie…” She whispered, her voice delicate as if she were afraid she could shatter me. I tried to reply, to reassure her that I was ok; that it was all just a big misunderstanding; that the reporter and the police had confused another couple for my parents. That they were back home sleeping, but ready to ground me for life tomorrow morning. However, my mind didn’t have control over my body anymore. “Jennifer, please! Stop laughing.” She whispered again, her eyes slowly drowning in a sea of tears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Laughing? That thick sound of laughter belonged to me? That can’t be right. Nothing of this is right. My parents aren’t dead, and I’m definitely not laughing. On their own, my fingers intertwined themselves through my thick hair and pulled hard on the strands, instantly inflicting pain.  All I wanted was for the reporter’s clear, perfect voice to shut up; for the human bodies in the now too small room, to stop giving me worried looks; for Katelyn to stop treating me like I was made of glass; for the feeling of my ears bleeding to disappear; for all this to just be a nightmare that I would wake up from. Any second now.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Future of Media</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/the-future-of-media"/>
   <updated>2015-04-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/the-future-of-media</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Far too often articles have proclaimed the future of mass media, and how one new and upcoming technology will revolutionize the industry, only to be forgotten and replaced by the new next best thing. However, one commonality can be found amongst these revolutionaries; they are all consumed through some form of technology. Be it smartphones, television or computers, all ideas we have regarding the future of media is related electronic devices, not print media. So, is traditional print media dying? Yes. However that’s not to say that print media will completely phase out of sight, relegated to hipsters and the technophobic, either unwilling or unable to adapt. Although subscription to traditional paper editions of newspapers, books, and textbooks have been waning over the decades as online newspapers and e-books have been skyrocketing in numbers, the printed page still remains a powerhouse industry, as many students can attest to after years of lugging massive textbooks to and from classes. Still,  It is clear that technology is the future of mass media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be difficult to predict the future of mass media; after all, it was only a few years ago that we thought 3-D TV was the future. One noticeable trend in recent months has been that of wearable technology. Smart watches have existed for a couple of years already and with the growth of the market, especially with Apple’s controversial entrance into the market, smart watches and other wearable technology hold a strong chance of becoming the technology from which we consume our media in the future.  A niche of wearable technology that holds the most capacity to amaze, and truly resembles what we have called the future of media consumption is virtual and augmented reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A part of many science fiction novels and movies, virtual reality has always seemed like a pipe dream to many people. However, over the past couple of months many strides, leaps, have even  been made in the realization of this technology. From the Oculus Rift, to Project Morpheus, many companies have created workable virtual reality headsets. And while many believe that virtual reality only applies to the extreme gamers, and not the masses, Facebook’s $2billion purchase of Oculus Rift shows their certainty on the widespread possibilities of the technology. Another less extreme variant of this technology is augmented reality; with Google Glass and Microsoft’s announcement of the HoloLense, it is clear that major companies are investing large amounts of money into the development of these technologies. Whether they produce another ‘3-D TV’ or revolutionize how we consume our media remains to be seen. After all, far too often articles have proclaimed the future of mass media.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Narcissism on Wings</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/opinions-to-die-for"/>
   <updated>2015-04-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/opinions-to-die-for</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On the 24 March 2015, Andreas Lubitz decided to kill himself and 149 other people by crashing a plane into the French Alps. When faced with such inexplicable events, it is a human evolutionary imperative to look for a neat, rational motivation. But as it is with most suicides, the concept of understanding is nonsensical. We do not have the answers. I do not think we even have the right question. There is no psychopathology to be made of the copilot of the Germanwings flight number 4U9525 from Barcelona to Dusseldorf. One man with no desire to live decided that his own wish to die on his own terms and in the way he wanted was more important than the lives of all the other passengers. People that did not want to die. People that wanted to go forward. And also, people who had just been born and had just started to live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lacan claims that suicide is one of the few ways humans distinguish themselves from animals. A human is not forced to say ‘yes’ to life unconditionally, and can choose to commit suicide if he/she believes all possibilities are exhausted. Morally questionable or not, suicide is a deeply human act. However, what happened on March 24&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; was not a deeply human act. It cannot even be defined as bestial. Possibly the only word that could somehow attempt to describe this event would be ‘narcissistic’. However, Narcissus did not bring 150 people along with himself to the bottom of that fateful pool. He drowned hopelessly alone, with only the consolation of finally exhausting his Ego. The narcissistic man is burdened and yet elated by his Ego. Being the receptacle of the most essential element of the universe is hard but rewarding work. Here, however, a distinction must be made between the narcissistic man and the depressed man who develops narcissistic tendencies. The former will never commit suicide, because he will do anything in his power to avoid feeling useless or will lose his grasp on reality. His Ego supports him and nourishes him. The latter, however, develops a feeling of uselessness or of being nothing, and it is this feeling that becomes his Ego. His own identity becomes decentralized and obsesses on his being nothing. This, in turn, makes him become an ‘opposite’ narcissist. He finds twisted pleasure in being nothing and in attempting to destroy his own Ego. From here, suicide becomes a simple step. And because he has idolized his feeling of uselessness to the level of linchpin of the world, if he is nothing, then the world itself must be nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what Lubitz did, albeit with a much greater human impact. He did not not consider the lives he was going to take. He considered them and took them because he believed that exhausting his Ego would exhaust the world. All the other people in the plane faded to faint shadows of the world that made him suffer when faced with the bright light of the supernova of his Ego, exploding in a terrible moment for the only and last time. The narcissist suicidal man kills himself to end his Ego, which he believes to be the linchpin of the world, and therefore by ending his life, he ends the world around him. This mentality explains people who murder their loved ones before committing suicide. It does not matter how many people I murdered before or with my suicide, because if I, the linchpin of the world, the epicenter of reality, am unimportant, then everything else must be useless and unimportant. His own obsession with his Ego as being useless and inconsequential led him to the terrible conclusion that everything else is useless and inconsequential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ‘opposite’ narcissist wants to destroy his Ego with the keenness of the severely depressed and with the desire for grandeur and immortality of the narcissist. His last act has to destroy his Ego in a personal way, but also make it immortal in an impersonal way. The people who die with him are nothing, just the means by which his act will be remembered. The people who die with him are nothing, just the extras to act as background. His hatred for life could not have left any survivors.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
