<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>The Royal Liar</title>
 <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/"/>
 <updated>2015-05-12T12:58:55+02:00</updated>
 <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>The Liars</name>
   <email>rl@marymountrome.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Alya J.</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/alya-j"/>
   <updated>2015-04-11T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/alya-j</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name:&lt;/strong&gt; Alya J.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Nickname:&lt;/strong&gt; Ally&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Grade:&lt;/strong&gt; 11&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Nationality:&lt;/strong&gt; Kuwaiti, Mexican American&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Years at MMI:&lt;/strong&gt; Almost 2 years&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Life motto:&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t be peanut butter and jealous and just give me some tater tots, dude. Ps. You should blow on this friendship rock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Celebrity crush?&lt;/em&gt; Seth Rogan, Chris Evans and Aaron Taylor Johnson.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Most awkward thing that ever happened to you?&lt;/em&gt; Mistaking the sex of little children when consulting their parents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;If your life were a song, what would the title be?&lt;/em&gt; Whoops, I did it again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Something you couldn’t live without?&lt;/em&gt; Cheeeeeeeeeessseee!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Someone you couldn’t live without?&lt;/em&gt; My best friends and family.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best thing that happened in 2014?&lt;/em&gt; The 1975 and Ed Sheeran concert.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you could have one superpower what would it be?&lt;/em&gt; Telekinesis!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Favorite subject?&lt;/em&gt; Chemistry, and music, Duh!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The perfect vacation?&lt;/em&gt; Somewhere where there’s Takis and an endless amount of good indie music.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cats or dogs?&lt;/em&gt; None! Sugar gliders. They’re so much cuter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Favorite artist?&lt;/em&gt; Wow. Dude: Morrissey, Chick: Etta James.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best thing that happened this month?&lt;/em&gt; My family from the states got to visit and that was really nice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best thing that happened ever?&lt;/em&gt; Too many fun and PG 13 things that include watching cartoons and a life time supply of pesto, of course!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Facebook or Instagram?&lt;/em&gt; Neither, tumbler.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Favorite holiday?&lt;/em&gt; Christmas (Says the Muslim).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Biggest surprise you’ve ever had?&lt;/em&gt; When I found out my mom was preggers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you could pick one historical figure to have coffee with, whom would you pick?&lt;/em&gt; Beethoven or Brahms. They seem like interesting psychotic people.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best gift you ever received?&lt;/em&gt; My life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Favorite country you visited?&lt;/em&gt; Spain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Number one goal in life?&lt;/em&gt; Being actually happy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Movie you laughed the hardest through?&lt;/em&gt; A Medea’s Christmas and Napoleon Dynamite 22. Best thing about living in Rome? Food and people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you could switch places with someone for a day, who would it be?&lt;/em&gt; No one, I’m pretty content with myself  .&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dream job?&lt;/em&gt; Professional musician.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who should everyone be following right now?&lt;/em&gt; Jon Gomm he’s great and really underrated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Ms. Ferrarin</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/ms-ferrarin"/>
   <updated>2015-04-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/ms-ferrarin</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ms. Ferrarin has been the drama teacher here at Marymount for the past six years and has directed a total of twelve shows with the Marymount players, the after school drama club.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interview conducted and transcribed by Ramzi Shatara.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R: How do you decide what musical or play you’re going to choose to do?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
F: Well, usually we think about the talent that we have. We think about all the people who have done musicals in the high school in the past, and we think about people who might be good, because we have to have an idea that we could possibly cast it [the musical] because it would be no good thinking of a show and then realizing we don’t have this character or that character or any possibility for a character.  So we think about what we have and then we come up with a list of possibilities. But for this show it was a bit different because I was almost, I was bullied into it by, [laughs] by a few little devils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R: For anyone who doesn’t know how it all works, what can you say about the process of putting it all together as a director? Do you make lists for yourself?Draw up set designs? What does it mean to be prepared when you come to rehearsal?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
F: Okay, yea, everything. All of that. It’s basically one of the biggest undertakings that you can do really because you have to have a vision of how it’s going to end, so you have to have an idea of what it’s going to look like or what you want it to look like. You might not get there but you have to have an understanding of what that might be. And you have to be as organized as possible so that all of those steps get completed. So there’s lots of list making, there’s basically a list a day for different things. You have to come up with a rehearsal schedule before auditions so you know you have enough time, so you have to work backwards. That’s basically it. It’s working backwards. It’s thinking of what you want the final thing to be and then working backwards and trying to fit everything in. And most of the time you can’t fit everything in, so you have to cram it in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R: Are there lots of times when you just have to improvise?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
F: Absolutely, there are plenty of times when you just have to skip over things or scenes because there is just no time. Time is the biggest factor. You just hope and pray that people go off and learn what they need to learn, so it’s really great as a director to have a cast who bring stuff to rehearsal and come prepared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R: Is there any piece of advice that you always find yourself giving to your actors?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
F: I think...probably...well, for a musical, I suppose the biggest one would be energy. Always. And for people who don’t know what that means, It would be bringing a certain level of energy onto the stage. So even if you make a big mistake or you don’t know what you’re doing you have to do it with confidence...because it’s incredible and very real, the sharing of energy between the audience and the actors. Also probably secondly, would be to make sure the story is told, because if the actor doesn’t understand their his or her and the story, they’re not going to be able to effectively tell it. Because that’s what it is at the end of the day. It’s a story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R: And not to take to themselves too seriously [laughs]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
F: Don’t take yourself too seriously! Yeah! Because otherwise you’re going to hold yourself back and not reach your true potential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R: What would you tell someone who has never really tried being in a play before, but wants to try?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
F: I would probably tell them that it would be completely different to what they expect. You get what you put in, with everything in life, but definitely something like that. You can adapt being apart of a performance like this to what you want to do, so if you want to do something huge and throw yourself in then go for a main role, if you just want to try it then come along and do a backstage roll and see how it’s done and build up your confidence that way. The most important thing is to try and have fun and we try and have fun and [laughs] sometimes I make it hard because I do lose my temper but that’s because I know that people can do it better than they are doing. It’s hard work but I think if you ask anyone and I challenge anyone to ask any cast member, past or present, how he or she felt at the end, they’ll tell you that they loved it. Because there’s nothing that compares to the moment that the curtains close and there’s an eruption of sound, and it’s all the actors and crew just letting off steam that they’ve managed to do it. The arts are for everybody, and everybody owns the arts, so even if you’ve never tried it before, its never too late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R: You’ve done twelve plays now at Marymount&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
F: Have I? [laughs]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R: Yea, it’s twelve as of West Side Story, so from the ones that you’ve done which were the most challenging and which was the most rewarding?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
F: The most challenging was West Side Story without a doubt. It was challenging because it’s a huge musical and it’s a musical that lots of people already know and love so the audience was coming in with big expectations and we had to meet them. So I really feel as a director and teacher, I want everyone to do their best. I want to do my best. So you push yourself and everyone else to make it happen. It was also very difficult musically. The most rewarding was probably...maybe because it was so difficult was West Side Story. But also maybe -- The one that I felt that I stretched
myself most as a director and I stretched the actors who I was working with was probably Twelve Angry Men. It was something new that we hadn’t done before and nothing we have done since. That was a real ensemble piece and I really like ensemble pieces because it means everyone is working together; everyone was on stage the entire time...it was tough, but really good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R: Can you give us any hints about next year’s shows?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
F: Can I? No, [laughs] I honestly have no idea what the shows will be, we kind of have ideas floating around, but we can’t choose until we see that list of people who sign up. So all I’ll say is that if you’re interested, sign up.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Afterlife, Frankenstein, and Reanimation</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/the-afterlife-frankenstein-and-reanimation"/>
   <updated>2015-04-09T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/the-afterlife-frankenstein-and-reanimation</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The thought of life after death has been with us since the beginning of mankind. This dates back to the Neanderthals and every civilization since. The Egyptians, from approximately 3100 to 332 BC, believed that immortality could be achieved if Pharaohs were mummified, bringing items with them to take to the afterlife. The person’s heart would then be weighed of sins, and depending on whether or not there were any, they would pass on or be devoured by Ammit, a demon. The Greeks, dating back to 800-500 BC, believed the souls of the deceased would be judged by Hades, the god of the underworld, and based on their sins or goodness, would be sent to either the fields of punishment or of peacefulness and content. Similarly, the Vikings, around 800-1066 AD, surmised that warriors would spend their afterlives in Valhalla, sinners in Hel, and others in Fólkvangr, a massive meadow to be reunited with loved ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of these civilizations, however, thought of bringing the dead back to life. In the late Romantic era, Mary Wollstonecraft Shelley thought of what might happen if a person were to be reassembled and reanimated through galvanism in the first ever science fiction novel, &lt;em&gt;Frankenstein&lt;/em&gt;. The main character, Dr. Victor Frankenstein, is able to successfully put together a creature capable of love, despite (spoiler alert) resulting in the deaths of almost every character. Her work brought forward lots of criticism on the religious and moral aspects of reanimating the dead, and instilled fear in societies that had just begun to embrace electricity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flash forward to the present, where patients are revived through resuscitation (CPR), or preserved through cryopreservation (freezing organisms in the hopes of being revived in the future) in almost every modern hospital. Science has come a long way since the Greeks and the Egyptians, and we, at &lt;em&gt;the Royal Liar&lt;/em&gt;, can’t help but wonder how much further it’ll advance. Globally, life expectancy rates are increasing, but with this come over population and a strain on resources. All of these are important factors to keep in mind when considering manipulating the inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Formula 1 2015 Starts Off in Melbourne</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/formula-1-2015-starts-off-in-melbourne"/>
   <updated>2015-04-08T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/formula-1-2015-starts-off-in-melbourne</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After Lewis Hamilton’s win in Abu Dhabi four months ago which granted him his second drivers’ championship, Formula 1 fans were anxious to see the changes to teams and drivers as well as the rules, but most of all they were ready for the start of the new season. There were a couple of changes to the rules this year, primarily the introduction of the virtual safety car.  After the Japanese Grand Prix in October 2014 where Jules Bianchi had an almost fatal accident, from which he is still recovering from today, the Fédération Internationale de l’Automobile (FIA) have introduce the virtual safety car; which will mean that drivers will have to slow down in areas where there has been a crash. Other changes to rules include the loss of double points during the last race. The drivers are now limited to four engines for the whole season and radio communication with the boxes will be restricted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest change, though, has been in the makeup of the teams. The title favorites are both of Mercedes’ star drivers, Lewis Hamilton and Nico Rosberg. Then there will probably be an interesting battle for the third place between the two Williams (Valtteri Bottas and Felipe Massa) and Ferrari (Sebastian Vettel and Kimi Räikkönen) drivers. Now that it seems that Ferrari is becoming more of a competitor it is clear that Fernando Alonso’s decision to leave the team for McLaren was misguided. Like Dani Pedrosa, who although not a F1 driver but a motorcycle racer, has the same misfortune as Alonso because has won three third places and three second places in Moto GP but never first. Now that Alonso has left Ferrari for McLaren who he thought had a more competitive car, Ferrari is fighting for the third place while the only McLaren that finished came in last. But the most surprising thing in the 2015 line-up has to be the 17 year-old rookie Max Verstappen who races for the Toro Rosso team, the sister team of Red Bull.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the first race of the season, it can be described as an overall fiasco. First of all, there were multiple mechanical problems, resulting in just a 75% of cars turning up on the grid for the first race. Of these 15 cars 4 of them had to drop out meaning that only 55% of the cars actually finished. Clearly this is not the path to attract more viewers to the already declining viewership of the once great sport. As it stands there are basically only two drivers with a true possibility at winning the title, Hamilton and Rosberg from the Mercedes team. Hamilton came in 1&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;sup&gt; and Rosberg 2&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; at Melbourne. Alonso, who could potentially be a contender for the top, but most likely won’t be able to compete due to a concussion he suffered from in his crash in Barcelona during testing. Hopefully he will recover in time to attend the next race in Malaysia on March 29th so that the season can get a little bit more interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Opinions to Die For</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/opinions-to-die-for"/>
   <updated>2015-04-07T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/opinions-to-die-for</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On February 27th of this year, mere minutes before midnight, Russian politician Boris Nemtsov was gunned down on a bridge next to the Kremlin in central Moscow. The killers sped off in a white vehicle, but 5 were apprehended a little over a week after the assassination, and a sixth blew himself up with a grenade before he could be arrested. All the men are ethnic Chechens, but an extremist Islamist motive behind the attack has been strongly refuted. Zaur Dadayev has been identified as the brain behind the operation, but Dadayev himself claimed that he was tortured and that the police forced him to confess, and has subsequently retracted both his claims of torture and confession. International media reporting on the homicide and its ensuing investigation always includes “Putin’s opponent” along with Nemtsov’s name in the segment or article title, blatantly implying Putin was partially or directly responsible for Boris Nemtsov’s unfortunate end. The victim’s own daughter recently proclaimed her father was  “the most powerful leader of the opposition in Russia” and a “fighter”. Indeed, the media has transformed Nemtsov into a sort of martyr-a rebel leader, someone who stood up to the infamous Putin, and a man who had opinions that he was ready to die for. These days, the western media regards anybody who is in opposition to Putin favorably. At the time of his death, Boris Nemtsov was working on a report that would prove the presence of the Russian military in Eastern Ukraine (even though such assertions have been vehemently denied). Less than three weeks before his assassination, Nemtsov admitted in an interview that he was afraid for his life. It seems like an open-and-shut case; Putin ordered the murder of his feared opponent Boris Nemtsov, and is now trying to cover it up. Except Putin never feared or had any reason to fear Boris Nemtsov, and the whole situation is much more complicated than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the early 90’s, Boris Nemtsov was a young, bureaucrat from a small, provincial Russian town. He attracted the attention of Boris Yeltsin, the first president of the Russian Federation, and immediately entered his inner circle. Boris Yeltsin chose his favorites not based on their political capabilities or achievements, but based on personal preference, and it wasn’t very hard to understand why he had picked the charismatic and good-natured Nemtsov.  For this reason, it’s not too farfetched to say that Boris Nemtsov was directly involved in ruling and exploiting the crumbling remains of the Soviet empire. Tons of people in Yeltsin’s inncer circle, along with Nemtsov and Yeltsin’s daughter amassed billions. Eventually, Yeltsin would publicly announce “I’m tired, I’m leaving.” and do everything in his power to pass on his position to Putin, who in return issued a decree that would protect Yeltsin and his family from any corruption charges. Once president, Putin swapped Yeltsin’s inner circle with his own cronies, which Boris Nemtsov was no longer a part of. Vladimir Putin followed in his predecessor’s footsteps and accumulated his own fortune, and Boris Nemtsov was left out and bitterly started his opposition campaign. Due to the fact Boris Nemtsov was an ordinary politician with no particular talent, most of his “opposition” took place in the provincial towns that he was from-far from Moscow, and Putin. In the past few years, Boris Nemtsov’s popularity level was extremely low, and many people did not know who he was. He lived a comfortable life with his young, model Ukranian girlfriend, and his murder left many wondering around the circumstances surrounding his death. Even though he was a forgotten political figure, his passing was a huge tragedy for the Russian people. The Russian media has a spectrum of theories and responses ranging from “Putin was responsible!” on the revolutionary TV channel “Rain” to theories that the West orchestrated the killing and make Putin the scapegoat. However, recently released information about Nemtsov may explain why he was even a murder target. Boris Nemtsov secretly cooperated with the United States, and assisted them in creating a list of Russian oligarchs and government officials to sanction. It is highly possible that one of the sanctioned victims had a vendetta against him, and decided to pursue it in the most lethal way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe that Nemtsov should have been judged over 20 years ago when he was in power and the right hand of president Yeltsin, and billions of dollars poured into Western banks. Though his death is undoubtedly devastating, Nemtsov should not be regarded as a “rebel hero”. His foray into becoming an oppositioner was motivated by his exclusion from the inner circle that had access to the financial resources of the country, and constantly stole from the people of Russia. He didn’t die for his opinions, he died because he betrayed the members of his “gang”.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Determined Royals Look on to Jubilant Season Finale</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/determined-royals-look-on-to-jubilant-season-finale"/>
   <updated>2015-04-07T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/determined-royals-look-on-to-jubilant-season-finale</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The first two games against Naples and Sigonella have already set a clear picture in the minds of those who have followed the DODDS tournament: the Royals Boys Soccer team is completely dominant in Italy. A 3-1 away win against perhaps the second strongest team, Naples, and an 8-0 annihilation of Sigonella are indicative of this. The team is perhaps the most united in the league, with each player giving 110% every time they take to the field and really playing for each other. The Royals are an example to be followed by all, in fact, even Italian Serie A giants AS Roma who are struggling and have been accused of being mercenaries who care for nothing but money. Rest assured that the Royals have something to play for each time they take the field, and justly rewarded the fans who flooded the stand to see them play Sigonella.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shall we take a brief look at the technical aspects that have enabled them to win thus far? First of all, there is the coach, Roberto Rossi, to thank. He is a man with a winning mentality, who advocates for high intensity and commitment whenever the team takes to the field, and knows how to maintain a balance of hard work and enjoyment. Secondly there is the defense, with Andrea Pregoni proving to be a worthy replacement of his brother alongside Giovanni Acampora. Rest assured that trying to get past these two is like running through a brick wall. The cement of this wall can be seen as Giammaria Montella, the goalkeeper who guides the team from his position. Up front there has been no shortage of goals, created by the industrious midfield and finished by a clinical attack led by the man of the moment: Diego Piorico. 6 out of the 11 goals are his, and the Royals will look to him to provide for them in the crucial games. In short, this is a team who starts strong and finishes stronger, and most importantly plays as a team with each player helping the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The remaining matches in Italy seem straightforward for the Royals, with away trips to Florence and Aviano, but watch out for the long awaited “derby” with AOSR. It is a game the Royals will go into brimming with confidence and enthusiasm, eager to bring home a win after having been held to a 2-2 draw last year. After that comes the European Championship with the Royals hoping to retain their 3 consecutive titles in Kaiserslautern. As they say in Italy, in fact: “Non c’è due senza tre e il quattro vien’ da sé”. This is a proverb the Royals will hope to fulfill, and crown the final year of the seniors in the squad, some of the which will unfortunately be unavailable due to exams.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Lotanna M.</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/lotanna-m"/>
   <updated>2015-04-06T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/lotanna-m</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name:&lt;/strong&gt; Lotanna M.
&lt;strong&gt;Nickname:&lt;/strong&gt; Lolo/Làlo/Lorenzo/Samuel
&lt;strong&gt;Grade:&lt;/strong&gt; 11
&lt;strong&gt;Nationality:&lt;/strong&gt; Nigerian
&lt;strong&gt;Years at MMI:&lt;/strong&gt; 5
&lt;strong&gt;Life motto:&lt;/strong&gt; If I don’t do it first, I want to do it better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Celebrity crush?&lt;/em&gt; Scarlett Johansson.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Most awkward thing that ever happened to you?&lt;/em&gt; Seeing Germano in the shower.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pepsi or coke?&lt;/em&gt; Coke.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Something you couldn’t live without?&lt;/em&gt; Soccer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Someone you couldn’t live without?&lt;/em&gt; My mother.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Number one goal in life?&lt;/em&gt; To do things I can’t imagine now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you could have one superpower, what would it be?&lt;/em&gt; Immortality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Favorite subject?&lt;/em&gt; Biology because Mr. Zinzi is my best friend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best money you ever spent?&lt;/em&gt; Buying a printer for school.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;3 things you’d take to a deserted island?&lt;/em&gt; Phone, ball, food.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best thing that happened in 2014?&lt;/em&gt; Become soccer champions for the 4th time in a row.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best thing that happened this month?&lt;/em&gt; Beating Sigonella by 8 goals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best thing that happened ever?&lt;/em&gt; Having brothers around me all the time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Movie you laughed the hardest through?&lt;/em&gt; The Dictator and Horrible Bosses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Favorite holiday?&lt;/em&gt; Christmas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Biggest surprise you’ve ever had?&lt;/em&gt; Trip to Budapest to see my big brother.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you could pick one historical figure to have coffee with, whom would you pick?&lt;/em&gt; Francesco Totti because he’s Francesco Totti.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Favorite country you visited?&lt;/em&gt; Colombia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Country you want to visit?&lt;/em&gt; Japan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Favorite artist?&lt;/em&gt; Kanye West.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cats or dogs?&lt;/em&gt; Dogs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best thing about living in Rome?&lt;/em&gt; AS Roma.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best gift you ever received?&lt;/em&gt; PS3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Weirdest word in the English language?&lt;/em&gt; Fella.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;If your life were a song, what would the title be?&lt;/em&gt; All I Do is Win.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>West Side Story: The Review</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/west-side-story-the-review"/>
   <updated>2015-04-05T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/west-side-story-the-review</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I went to see the Marymount Players preform the iconic American musical: &lt;em&gt;West Side Story&lt;/em&gt;, directed by Gina Ferrarin, on the opening night, and I have to say that overall I was impressed.  The story is inspired by William Shakespeare’s tragedy &lt;em&gt;Romeo and Juliet&lt;/em&gt;; however it is set in New York’s Upper West Side in the 1950’s. The musical explores the rivalry between the Jets, an American gang, and the Sharks, who are from Puerto Rico, taunted by the Jets for their ethnicity. The rivalry between the two gangs ends when former Jet leader, Tony (Ramzi Shatara) falls in love with the leader of the Sharks, Bernardo’s (Michele Musilli) sister, Maria (Azzurra Moores). Of course, being based on Shakespeare’s tragedy, the rivalry between the two gangs will only end with the tragic end of the “star-crossed lovers’” love story, resulting in Tony’s death and Maria’s desperation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The relationship between the entire cast was comfertable and realistic, resulting in a successful suspension of disbelief for the audience. The female characters, Maria and her best friend/brother’s girlfriend, Anita (Alya Juahili), had great chemistry on stage and sang harmoniously together. Moores portayed a naive and quite fanciful Maria, perfectly reflecting the démodé character. Alya played a sassy and hopeful Anita, which presented a nice contrast to Maria, enhancing their relationship even more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The male protagonists Tony, his best friend Riff (Giulio Starace) and Bernardo (Musilli) also interpreted their roles very well. Like Moores, Shatara offered a naive and sensitive protagonist who was juxtaposed to every other male character in the play, making him stand out from the cast. Starace also interpreted the role of the Jets’ leader well and skillfully developed the character of an American stud, which turned out to be softer than what the audience expected. Musilli also played a charismatic and credible Bernardo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the cast was also very good: the Jets hilarious and modern in comparison to the rest of the play, and the Shark girls charmingly portrayed the expectations and dreams of Puerto Rican girls living in America in the 1950’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The music of the play was by far the best element of the performance. The cherubic voice of Azzurra Moores in the last song gave me chills, and the performance of Azzura Moores, Costanza Filì, Roberta Sidotti and Elle Pinkerton in “I Feel Pretty” was incredibly enjoyable. Shatara and Moores’ duet in “Tonight” was also exceptional; however, due to technical problems with the microphones, sometimes one of the two voices was less audible. The best song was definitely “America” with Alya’s amazing voice leading the Sharks in a fun and well-performed act. The band led by Rocco Sbardella accompanied the actors superbly, enhancing the lyrics, voices and instrumental elements of the band. Mr. Sbardella did a great job conducting and teaching the songs to the actors and band alike, delivering a professional performance. The only criticism I have is that sometimes the band was too loud relative to the actors’ voices.
The directing by Ms. Ferrarin was impeccable as always, producing a school production that can definitely compete with some semi-professional companies in Italy. The exits, entrances, changes of scenery, lighting, blocking, and preparation of the actors were evidently a success. A fine example of this was the love scene between Maria and Tony, which was conducted with elegance and refined taste, enhancing their sentiment of true love that is central to the entire play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulations and well done to all!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Terminator T-1000 Prototype is Here</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/terminator-t-1000-prototype-is-here"/>
   <updated>2015-04-04T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/terminator-t-1000-prototype-is-here</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The T-1000 is a terrifying, shape-shifting liquid-metal robot from &lt;em&gt;Terminator 2&lt;/em&gt;. It is capable of transforming into anything, and it can pass through any small opening. This is one of those science fiction ideas, that seems impossible and made-up. But as we know, science-fiction has the potential to become real in the future. It turns out that this is the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This amazing discovery was made by a group of scientists in Tsinghua University in Beijing, China. They took a drop of gallium, which is liquid just under 30ºC, added some indium and tin, and placed it in sodium hydroxide, a liquid similar to salt water. Then, they dropped a flake of aluminum on the liquid-metal droplet. It immediately began to bubble, and started spinning really fast — so fast that it started moving on its own. So they thought, where can we use this? Well, it turns out that there are two main usages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is transportation. Because the metal is a liquid, it can bend and adjust to the path that it&amp;#39;s travelling in. By path, I mean like pipes. These droplets can move through twisted, thin pipes with ease. This can be useful when we want to transport things to places with hard access. We can create a larger droplet that can carry supplies inside, and they will be able to reach these places by morphing themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second is pumping. If we keep the droplet in place, it will keep spinning in place — the liquid around it will move instead of the droplet. This means that we can create smaller circuits without the need for a huge pump. We just need to drop one of these droplets inside! For example, we could make a cooling device without the need for a power supply. We just add the droplet, feed it with aluminum, and it works automatically!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also succeeded in making shapes with this droplet. We apply a little current, and depending on the current, the droplet will change shape. As long as the current&amp;#39;s there, the shape remains. The scientists made a tree-like shape, but it wasn&amp;#39;t that precise because they didn&amp;#39;t know how to handle it properly. If we find out the proper way to do this, we could make it look like a tree, a cloud, or anything we imagine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just the entry step of making a T-1000. We can&amp;#39;t really call it prototype. However, as we keep investigating, we might really be able to make robots that can change shape on the fly. We just need to know how this works. That means, there is still a whole lot of potential. Will we be able to actually create a T-1000? I believe, some day, yes.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Fake Brat: Part V</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/fake-brat-part-v"/>
   <updated>2015-04-03T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/fake-brat-part-v</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;“Jacobe Moorse and Cassandra Moorse instantly dead in a car accident seconds after their exit from the Royal Hotel.” The reporter’s voice played like a broken record in my head, as though it was taunting me. It couldn’t be real; none of this was real. Death couldn’t just tear my parents away from me. There was just so much we still had to figure out, so much we still needed to fix. My father still had to tell my mother he was cheating on her. My mother still had to learn what was going on in my life. We still had to have at least a moment where we could be an actual family. See, they can’t be gone.  There is just too much we still need to do. Too much we need to tell each other that I have tell them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kneeled; the dust of the old apartment suffocated me as I shivered. The room was still. All I could hear was of the sound my heart beating too fast in my ears mixed with someone’s thick laugh echoing along the walls of the room. I watched the television hesitantly, as it broadcasted footage from the scene. The limousine I was in with them only hours ago: destroyed, crushed and squashed in the middle of an intersection. A truck lay on its side a few meters away.  Red and blue lights reflected off the shattered pieces of glass on the road. Three human size black bags lay on the dull dark road next to an ambulance. The person’s laugh continued to reverberate through the lifeless room, the sound slowly getting louder and closer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A soft hand abruptly moved a strand of hair away from my face. My eyes flickered as I recognized the hand as Katelyn. She was so close that I could detect the small strands of brown in her eyes encircled by her eyelashes that were painted on with a thick layer of mascara. Her face filled with millions of emotions and yet I couldn’t feel anything. Physically my body felt dull and jaded, but mentally I felt like a stranger to emotions, and analyzing my surroundings became all of the sudden easier, as if my feelings were a fog hiding me from the clearer details. “Sweetie…” She whispered, her voice delicate as if she were afraid she could shatter me. I tried to reply, to reassure her that I was ok; that it was all just a big misunderstanding; that the reporter and the police had confused another couple for my parents. That they were back home sleeping, but ready to ground me for life tomorrow morning. However, my mind didn’t have control over my body anymore. “Jennifer, please! Stop laughing.” She whispered again, her eyes slowly drowning in a sea of tears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Laughing? That thick sound of laughter belonged to me? That can’t be right. Nothing of this is right. My parents aren’t dead, and I’m definitely not laughing. On their own, my fingers intertwined themselves through my thick hair and pulled hard on the strands, instantly inflicting pain.  All I wanted was for the reporter’s clear, perfect voice to shut up; for the human bodies in the now too small room, to stop giving me worried looks; for Katelyn to stop treating me like I was made of glass; for the feeling of my ears bleeding to disappear; for all this to just be a nightmare that I would wake up from. Any second now.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Future of Media</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/the-future-of-media"/>
   <updated>2015-04-02T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/the-future-of-media</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Far too often articles have proclaimed the future of mass media, and how one new and upcoming technology will revolutionize the industry, only to be forgotten and replaced by the new next best thing. However, one commonality can be found amongst these revolutionaries; they are all consumed through some form of technology. Be it smartphones, television or computers, all ideas we have regarding the future of media is related electronic devices, not print media. So, is traditional print media dying? Yes. However that’s not to say that print media will completely phase out of sight, relegated to hipsters and the technophobic, either unwilling or unable to adapt. Although subscription to traditional paper editions of newspapers, books, and textbooks have been waning over the decades as online newspapers and e-books have been skyrocketing in numbers, the printed page still remains a powerhouse industry, as many students can attest to after years of lugging massive textbooks to and from classes. Still,  It is clear that technology is the future of mass media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be difficult to predict the future of mass media; after all, it was only a few years ago that we thought 3-D TV was the future. One noticeable trend in recent months has been that of wearable technology. Smart watches have existed for a couple of years already and with the growth of the market, especially with Apple’s controversial entrance into the market, smart watches and other wearable technology hold a strong chance of becoming the technology from which we consume our media in the future.  A niche of wearable technology that holds the most capacity to amaze, and truly resembles what we have called the future of media consumption is virtual and augmented reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A part of many science fiction novels and movies, virtual reality has always seemed like a pipe dream to many people. However, over the past couple of months many strides, leaps, have even  been made in the realization of this technology. From the Oculus Rift, to Project Morpheus, many companies have created workable virtual reality headsets. And while many believe that virtual reality only applies to the extreme gamers, and not the masses, Facebook’s $2billion purchase of Oculus Rift shows their certainty on the widespread possibilities of the technology. Another less extreme variant of this technology is augmented reality; with Google Glass and Microsoft’s announcement of the HoloLense, it is clear that major companies are investing large amounts of money into the development of these technologies. Whether they produce another ‘3-D TV’ or revolutionize how we consume our media remains to be seen. After all, far too often articles have proclaimed the future of mass media.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Narcissism on Wings</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/opinions-to-die-for"/>
   <updated>2015-04-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/04/opinions-to-die-for</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On the 24 March 2015, Andreas Lubitz decided to kill himself and 149 other people by crashing a plane into the French Alps. When faced with such inexplicable events, it is a human evolutionary imperative to look for a neat, rational motivation. But as it is with most suicides, the concept of understanding is nonsensical. We do not have the answers. I do not think we even have the right question. There is no psychopathology to be made of the copilot of the Germanwings flight number 4U9525 from Barcelona to Dusseldorf. One man with no desire to live decided that his own wish to die on his own terms and in the way he wanted was more important than the lives of all the other passengers. People that did not want to die. People that wanted to go forward. And also, people who had just been born and had just started to live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lacan claims that suicide is one of the few ways humans distinguish themselves from animals. A human is not forced to say ‘yes’ to life unconditionally, and can choose to commit suicide if he/she believes all possibilities are exhausted. Morally questionable or not, suicide is a deeply human act. However, what happened on March 24&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; was not a deeply human act. It cannot even be defined as bestial. Possibly the only word that could somehow attempt to describe this event would be ‘narcissistic’. However, Narcissus did not bring 150 people along with himself to the bottom of that fateful pool. He drowned hopelessly alone, with only the consolation of finally exhausting his Ego. The narcissistic man is burdened and yet elated by his Ego. Being the receptacle of the most essential element of the universe is hard but rewarding work. Here, however, a distinction must be made between the narcissistic man and the depressed man who develops narcissistic tendencies. The former will never commit suicide, because he will do anything in his power to avoid feeling useless or will lose his grasp on reality. His Ego supports him and nourishes him. The latter, however, develops a feeling of uselessness or of being nothing, and it is this feeling that becomes his Ego. His own identity becomes decentralized and obsesses on his being nothing. This, in turn, makes him become an ‘opposite’ narcissist. He finds twisted pleasure in being nothing and in attempting to destroy his own Ego. From here, suicide becomes a simple step. And because he has idolized his feeling of uselessness to the level of linchpin of the world, if he is nothing, then the world itself must be nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what Lubitz did, albeit with a much greater human impact. He did not not consider the lives he was going to take. He considered them and took them because he believed that exhausting his Ego would exhaust the world. All the other people in the plane faded to faint shadows of the world that made him suffer when faced with the bright light of the supernova of his Ego, exploding in a terrible moment for the only and last time. The narcissist suicidal man kills himself to end his Ego, which he believes to be the linchpin of the world, and therefore by ending his life, he ends the world around him. This mentality explains people who murder their loved ones before committing suicide. It does not matter how many people I murdered before or with my suicide, because if I, the linchpin of the world, the epicenter of reality, am unimportant, then everything else must be useless and unimportant. His own obsession with his Ego as being useless and inconsequential led him to the terrible conclusion that everything else is useless and inconsequential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ‘opposite’ narcissist wants to destroy his Ego with the keenness of the severely depressed and with the desire for grandeur and immortality of the narcissist. His last act has to destroy his Ego in a personal way, but also make it immortal in an impersonal way. The people who die with him are nothing, just the means by which his act will be remembered. The people who die with him are nothing, just the extras to act as background. His hatred for life could not have left any survivors.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Fake Brat: Part V</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/03/fake-brat-part-v"/>
   <updated>2015-03-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/03/fake-brat-part-v</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;“Jacobe Moorse and Cassandra Moorse instantly dead in a car accident seconds after their exit from the Royal Hotel.” The reporter’s voice played like a broken record in my head, as though it was taunting me. It couldn’t be real; none of this was real. Death couldn’t just tear my parents away from me. There was just so much we still had to figure out, so much we still needed to fix. My father still had to tell my mother he was cheating on her. My mother still had to learn what was going on in my life. We still had to have at least a moment where we could be an actual family. See, they can’t be gone.  There is just too much we still need to do. Too much we need to tell each other; that I have tell them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kneeled; the dust of the old apartment suffocated me as I shivered. The room was still. All I could hear was of the sound my heart beating too fast in my ears mixed with someone’s thick laugh echoing along the walls of the room. I watched the television hesitantly, as it broadcasted footage from the scene. The limousine I was in with them only hours ago: destroyed, crushed and squashed in the middle of an intersection. A truck lay on its side a few meters away.  Red and blue lights reflected off the shattered pieces of glass on the road. Three human size black bags lay on the dull dark road next to an ambulance. The person’s laugh continued to reverberate through the lifeless room, the sound slowly getting louder and closer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A soft hand abruptly moved a strand of hair away from my face. My eyes flickered as I recognized the hand as Katelyn. She was so close that I could detect the small strands of brown in her eyes encircled by her eyelashes that were painted on with a thick layer of mascara. Her face filled with millions of emotions and yet I couldn’t feel anything. Physically my body felt dull and jaded, but mentally I felt like a stranger to emotions, and analyzing my surroundings became all of the sudden easier, as if my feelings were a fog hiding me from the clearer details. “Sweaty…” She whispered. Her voice delicate as if she were afraid she could shatter me. I tried to reply, to reassure her that I was ok; that it was all just a big misunderstanding; that the reporter and the police had confused another couple for my parents. That they were back home sleeping, but ready to ground me for life tomorrow morning. However, my mind didn’t have control over my body anymore. “Jennifer, please! Stop laughing.” She whispered again, her eyes slowly drowning in a sea of tears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Laughing? That thick sound of laughter belonged to me? That can’t be right. Nothing of this is right. My parents aren’t dead and I’m definitely not laughing. On their own, my fingers intertwined themselves through my thick hair and pulled hard on the strands, instantly inflicting pain.  All I wanted was for the reporter’s clear, perfect voice to shut up; for the human bodies in the now too small room, to stop giving me worried looks; for Katelyn to stop treating me like I was made of glass; for the feeling of my ears bleeding to disappear; for all this just being a nightmare that I would wake up from in any second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To be continued…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>It's Nuclear Fear Again</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/03/its-nuclear-fear-again"/>
   <updated>2015-03-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/03/its-nuclear-fear-again</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;“We are optimistic”, or at least that is what we are being told by politicians for over 50 years. Attempts to get rid of nuclear weapons are always on the table, yet, now they seem more urgent as their threat to peace is more evident than ever. The Obama administration has called for a called for a global effort to reduce reliance on nuclear weapons. The ultimate goal, they wrote in the Wall Street Journal, should be to remove the threat such weapons pose completely. This almost Utopian view of the world has generated a swift response by academics, non-profit organizations and politicians to develop a nuclear policy line. A pressure group, , Global Zero, was set up to campaign for complete nuclear disarmament. Its aims were endorsed by scores of government leaders, present and past, and hundreds of thousands of citizens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worldwide, every nuclear power is spending a lavish amount of money to increase their atomic arsenal. Russia’s defence budget has grown by over 50% since 2007. China, long a nuclear minnow, is adding to its stocks and investing heavily in submarines and mobile missile batteries. Pakistan is amassing dozens of battlefield nukes to make up for its inferiority to India in conventional forces. North Korea is thought to be capable of adding a warhead a year. Even in the US, the Nobel peace laureate in the White House has asked Congress for almost $350 billion to undertake a decade-long program of modernization of America’s arsenal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The worst of all in this situation is volatility of countries with nuclear power. Throughout the Cold War the two superpowers to avoid an end of the world scenario, or Armageddon, tolerated the status quo. Nowadays, instead, there is no certainty of the countries’ intentions. Some countries demand nuclear power to guard themselves from the bordering states. Pakistan reassures that the weapons are safe, still we fear that these weapons could fall into the wrong hands, lets say ISIS or Al-Qaeda. As long as great-power relations remain unstable, regional rivalries linger unresolved and rogue states continue to see nuclear weapons as a way of intimidating purportedly powerful adversaries, the incentive to hang on to nuclear weapons will outweigh other considerations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important thing to do might seem to revitalize nuclear diplomacy. Hence, it will mean defending the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty, which stalls the spread of weapons and reassures neighboring countries. The danger remains as countries as Iran will enable signatories to enrich and reprocess the preparation for a bomb of their own—escalating the whole preparation for nuclear weapons. Then, what we can achieve now is to find ways to enact an effective deterrence, bear down on proliferation and re-start arms-control negotiations between the main nuclear powers.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>From Bankrupt to Bankable</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/03/from-bankrupt-to-bankable"/>
   <updated>2015-03-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/03/from-bankrupt-to-bankable</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Marvel Studios is a major film studio that occupies a vast chunk in the motion picture industry-it’s a money-making superhero industry that rakes in hundreds of millions of dollars annually. With an ever-growing quantity of superhero movies being released to quench the public’s voracious appetite, Marvel continues to produce some of the world’s most popular blockbusters. Little do most people know that less than 20 years ago, Marvel had entered bankruptcy in 1996. After peaking in the early 90’s, Marvel’s stock value collapsed after a catastrophic sequence of controversial business deals that cost approximately $700 million, and the comic book market crumbled. The company was drowning in debt, and as it didn’t have the money nor the time required to make its own films, ended up selling several of their major characters on lease deals. If the studio that bought the character didn’t use it within an interval of seven years, then Marvel would regain “custody”. Eventually, they would get the right of many characters back including fan favorites such as Iron Man, Captain America, and Thor but would also lose the opportunity of making hundreds of millions of dollars on Spider-Man and X-Men, owned by Sony and Fox respectively. After producing its first two successful films in 2008 (&lt;em&gt;Iron Man&lt;/em&gt; and The &lt;em&gt;Incredible Hulk&lt;/em&gt;), Marvel was purchased by Disney in 2009 for $4 billion, and the rest is history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2015 is an especially historic and event-filled year for Marvel-they’re introducing a new superhero (Ant-Man) in his very own feature length movie this summer, and their third ever TV show will premiere on Netflix on April 10th. In early February, they also partnered up with Sony Pictures to bring a new version of Spider-Man to the screen with a completely new main actor and creative direction. This exciting development means that there are probably going to be characters from the Marvel Cinematic Universe in Spider-Man films and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, we will definitely be seeing a lot of Marvel and Spidey in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Europe Launches a Mini Space Plane, IXV</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/03/europe-launches-a-mini-space-plane-ixv"/>
   <updated>2015-03-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/03/europe-launches-a-mini-space-plane-ixv</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;First of all, what is a Space Plane?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A space plane is a vehicle that is able to operate like an aircraft and a spacecraft, so basically it can fly in the Earth’s atmosphere as well as in space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What is IXV?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is the European Space Agency’s (ESA) unmanned &lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;ntermediate e&lt;strong&gt;X&lt;/strong&gt;perimental &lt;strong&gt;V&lt;/strong&gt;ehicle, which has the ability to decelerate from hypersonic speed, which is 5 times the speed of sound (Mach 5), to supersonic speed, which is a speed over the speed of sound (Mach 1). It is 5 meters long and weighs just under 2 tones. The IXV also includes over 300 advanced sensors that are able to record very important data, which will be analyzed by the ESA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What happened with the launching of IXV?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was launched on February 11th 2015 at 13:40 GMT in Kourou, French Guiana, a country bordering northern Brazil. The IXV was attached to a Vega rocket and detached at an altitude of 340 km and then continued up and reached the height of 412 km. It had a successful reentry, which has been described as “flawless” by the ESA, in the Earth’s atmosphere and landed in the Pacific Ocean just west of the Galapagos Islands. The reentry speed was 7.5 km/s at an altitude of 120 km and in total the mission, from launch to splashdown, lasted 100 minutes. The 2-tone space plane used a parachute to complete the decent into the Pacific and was kept afloat by balloons after which it was picked up by the “Nos Aries” ship and brought back to the ESA’S Technical center in the Netherlands for further examination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Why is this mission so important?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Giorgio Tumino, the IXV’s project manager said, “this was a short mission with big impact.” This suborbital mission has opened the door to developing a vehicle that is able to reenter in the earth’s atmosphere without being destroyed and which can then be reused. As Jean-Jacques Dordain, ESA Director General, has explicated, “IXV has opened a new chapter for ESA in terms of reentry capabilities and reusability.” The ESA has stated that initial results are projected to be announced about 6 weeks after the launch.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A First Glance at the Extended Essay</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/03/a-first-glance-at-the-extended-essay"/>
   <updated>2015-03-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/03/a-first-glance-at-the-extended-essay</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the most traumatic experience for every IB student is writing the extended essay, a compulsory piece of work, which contributes to 3 extra points on the final IB score. As a member of the Grade 11 class, I have recently had the opportunity to be introduced to the whole process of the extended essay and have found it to be challenging and confusing, but at the same time mildly enjoyable. In this article I will attempt to illustrate this in as a thorough a way as can possibly be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The extended essay, affectionately known by IB students around the world as EE, is the epitome of the IB diploma. The work itself reflects everything that defines the diploma: hard work, precision, time management, and about 20 individual deadlines that have to be met with maximum precision. In short, it is every student’s nightmare, but if done properly it can provide those extra points that are so vital to applying to certain courses in university. This is why I have found the whole process intriguing thus far, and even though I still do not have a clear idea, I am thankful for the thinking that the EE has generated, and the fact that it has allowed me to broaden my “horizons”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am wholly satisfied with the EE program offered at MMI, as are all of my fellow peers, but wish to draw to attention one gaping flaw in the whole program: the choice of advisors. Once you have in fact chosen the subject and teacher you would like to work with, it is basically a free for all to chose the person you desire to aid you in this ever so important piece of work. It just is not practical to have have students do an essay they do not want to complete just because they can’t get an advisor. How can this be changed? It is paramount that every student has an equal opportunity, and as a result there should be enough teachers to take students for ever subject of preference. This is quite hard to achieve, but can be reached through the adoption of a new selection program. Time should not be an issue, and people who hand in a proposal to an advisor before anyone else should not have preference over others. Instead, all proposition forms should be submitted within a deadline, and considered all at the same time, regardless of submission time. As it is perfectly understandable that teachers cannot take everyone, choices have to be made on the basis on HL and SL students, with higher level having preference, and the student showing the most interest and proposing the most interesting areas of study getting the edge. In conclusion, it would be amazing if every student had the opportunity to pursue their essay of interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To end this article, I would like to give a few tips on how to best face the extended essay, coming from my first month or so being involved in it. My first piece of advice to all of you students who will have to write the extended essay is to start thinking about it early, and to pay attention in the seminars to get the best possible start to the extended essay. Second and perhaps essential; thoroughly read through the Extended Essay Booklet. This is extremely helpful and will provide you with all of the information needed to tackle this extremely difficult piece of work. Finally, be prepared to be the first person to submit a request to your advisor, as it is quite literally a footrace to get to him/her first. It is a hard and confusing process, but it is never too late to change, and all becomes easier thanks to the staff at MMI.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Women that Changed the World</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/03/women-that-changed-the-world"/>
   <updated>2015-03-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/03/women-that-changed-the-world</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There is no questioning the fact that women in society are undermined. All throughout history, women haven’t enjoyed the same freedoms as men. For example, until recently, women weren’t allowed to work, did not receive equal pay, and were not granted voting rights. While in many MEDC this is no longer a problem, women in many countries are still denied these basic human rights. International Women’s Day however, celebrates all that women have accomplished economically, politically and socially. Proposed by Clara Zetkin, leader of the Women’s Office for the Social Democratic Party in Germany, in 1910, and passed at the International Conference of Working Women in Copenhagen, Women’s Day was first held on March 19th. More than 30,000 women attended street demonstrations across Europe that day. In 1917, working women in Saint Petersburg took to the streets on the last Sunday of February (March 8th in the Gregorian calendar) to strike for “Bread and Peace”, demanding an end to czarism, WWI, and food shortage in Russia. March 8th was deemed an official holiday in the USSR by Lenin and the Bolshevik party after the October (November according to the Gregorian calendar) Revolution. Other communist nations, such as China and Spain, followed in making this an official holiday. In 1977 the United Nations General Assembly made March 8th an internationally recognized day for world peace and women’s rights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ada Lovelace (1815-1852)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The founder of scientific computing. Ada studied mathematics extensively, and at the age of 17 met with Cambridge professor Charles Babbage to work on a calculating machine. This later became known as the analytical engine, which although never fully assembled, still incorporated elements of a modern computer such as coding and programming.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marie Curie (1867-1934)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The first woman to win a Nobel Prize, earn a doctorate in Europe and teach at a university. Her investigation contributed to the discovery of radioactivity and the elements Polonium and Radium.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amelia Earhart (1897-1937)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The first woman to fly across the Atlantic Ocean. In her attempt to be the first person to circumnavigate the world, Amelia’s plane deteriorated and was never found again; nonetheless, her initiative inspire female pilots all around the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Margaret Thatcher (1925-2013)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Known as the “Iron Lady”, she is the first woman to be democratically elected Prime Minister in European history. Margaret Thatcher was later reelected three times, and is remembered for her political genius and effective decision making.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aung San Suu Kyi (1945-)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Attempted to established a democratic government through peaceful means in Burma, she was however placed under house arrest for the next several years. In spite of this, Aung San Suu Kyi was still awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 1991.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Malala Yousafazi (1997-)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Began advocating for equal educational rights at the age of eleven in Pakistan, as well as risking Taliban attacks but continued blogging for BBC. After recovering from being shot in the head on her way home from school, she continued promoting education by speaking at the United Nations and confronting Obama on the issue of drone attacks. Most recently, the age of 17, Malala was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize and is the youngest person to have ever won this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Hydrogen for the Eco-Friendly Generation</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/03/hydrogen-for-the-eco-friendly-generation"/>
   <updated>2015-03-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/03/hydrogen-for-the-eco-friendly-generation</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Are you Eco-friendly? Environmental pollution has always been an issue in the 21st century. Ever since we noticed that we were running out of fossil fuel, there has been a need for a new energy source that does not run out and is reliable. Scientists came up with solar power, wind power, and many other alternative energy sources, and they made progress; however, none of these were powerful enough to completely replace our current use of oil and gas. Amongst these researchers, Toyota, a motor company, succeeded in developing their idea of using Hydrogen as a new source of energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hydrogen is the most abundant element in the universe. It has powered stars for billions of years, which provide heat and light for Earth. Hydrogen is indeed highly capable of replacing fossil fuel. Hydrogen is plentiful easy to obtain as well, as it is in water and air. Toyota is trying to harness this potentially clean energy source, through actively developing and producing fuel cell vehicles (FCV).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do you actually make energy from hydrogen? First, hydrogen is stored inside a tank where gasoline would normally be in. Oxygen is obtained from air. These two elements chemically combine inside a fuel cell, generating electricity to power the motor. The waste product is, surprisingly, water! No carbon-dioxide, no methane, no harmful gases! Because its resource and waste are both environmentally friendly, hydrogen-powered fuel cells are an awesome replacement for gasoline engines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using this amazing technology, Toyota has created the first commercial fuel cell vehicle called the Toyota Mirai (Japanese for ‘Future’). It was available in Japan since last year, and will be available globally this year. This car features a full hydrogen-powered fuel cell, and 0 carbon-dioxide emission. It is silent and smooth, takes only 3 minutes to recharge, and has a cruising range of 650 km — comparable to a normal gasoline-powered vehicle today. It can also act as a battery to power a house in case of a blackout. Overall, this car is a miraculous machine, which proves that hydrogen is truly an alternative to gasoline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the release of Mirai shows stability in hydrogen power, there is still a need for improvements. One example is the process of obtaining hydrogen. We normally use electrolysis to obtain hydrogen from water. However, this costs a lot. Unless a new method to obtain pure hydrogen is discovered, this plan will meet a stall in cost problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Ramzi S.</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/03/ramzi-s"/>
   <updated>2015-03-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/03/ramzi-s</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name:&lt;/strong&gt; Ramzi S.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Nickname:&lt;/strong&gt; Chabita&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Grade:&lt;/strong&gt; 12&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Nationality:&lt;/strong&gt; Canadian&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Years at MMI:&lt;/strong&gt; 7&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Life motto:&lt;/strong&gt; “I don’t hate you ‘cause you’re fat. You’re fat ‘cause I hate you!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Celebrity crush?&lt;/em&gt; Kerry Washington. Anyone who watches Scandal will understand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Most awkward thing that ever happened to you?&lt;/em&gt; I’m more awkward than Jennifer Lawrence at the Oscars.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;If your life were a song, what would the title be?&lt;/em&gt; “Love It”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Something you couldn’t live without?&lt;/em&gt; My closet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Someone you couldn’t live without?&lt;/em&gt; P.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best thing that happened in 2014?&lt;/em&gt; Getting accepted into Tisch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you could have one superpower what would it be?&lt;/em&gt; The ability to eat chocolate with no weight gain.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Favorite subject?&lt;/em&gt; Drama.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The perfect vacation?&lt;/em&gt; A vacation is perfect when you start forgetting what day it is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cats or dogs?&lt;/em&gt; Dogs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Favorite artist?&lt;/em&gt; Beyoncé, I love R&amp;amp;B.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best thing that happened this month?&lt;/em&gt; Performing West Side Story.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best thing that happened ever?&lt;/em&gt; The runaway llamas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Facebook or Instagram?&lt;/em&gt; The gram. All the way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Favorite holiday?&lt;/em&gt; New Years Eve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Biggest surprise you’ve ever had?&lt;/em&gt; Finding out that Morocco was not in South America…geography is not my strong suit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you could pick one historical figure to have coffee with, whom would you pick?&lt;/em&gt; Does Liza Minnelli count as a historical figure?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best gift you ever received?&lt;/em&gt; Good DNA (shout out to Naj!).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Favorite country you visited?&lt;/em&gt; Singapore.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Number one goal in life?&lt;/em&gt; To inspire a celeb’s break-up album.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Movie you laughed the hardest through?&lt;/em&gt; Bridesmaids killed me.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best thing about living in Rome?&lt;/em&gt; Ginger! (Not the spice, the restaurant/café).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you could switch places with someone for a day, who would it be?&lt;/em&gt; Lena Dunham!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dream job?&lt;/em&gt; To run my own show on HBO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who should everyone be following right now?&lt;/em&gt; @chrisellelim has the best Instagram!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Azzurra M.</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/03/azzurra-m"/>
   <updated>2015-03-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/03/azzurra-m</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name:&lt;/strong&gt; Azzurra M.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Nickname:&lt;/strong&gt; Zurrs, Azzi, Azz&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Grade:&lt;/strong&gt; 11&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Nationality:&lt;/strong&gt; British/Italian&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Years at MMI:&lt;/strong&gt; 3&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Life motto:&lt;/strong&gt; “Eat, Sleep, Knit. Repeat”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Celebrity crush?&lt;/em&gt; Eddie Redmayne in “My Week with Marilyn”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Most awkward thing that ever happened to you?&lt;/em&gt; Walking round the supermarket with swollen cheeks, after having two of my wisdom teeth removed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;If your life were a song, what would the title be?&lt;/em&gt; Grandma Blues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Something you couldn’t live without?&lt;/em&gt; My bed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Someone you couldn’t live without?&lt;/em&gt; P.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best thing that happened in 2014?&lt;/em&gt; In October I performed at the International IB Conference in front of over 1000 people, with one of my closest friends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you could have one superpower what would it be?&lt;/em&gt; Teleportation! I hate traffic and all means of transportation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Favorite subject?&lt;/em&gt; History&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The perfect vacation?&lt;/em&gt; Anything that involves shopping, good places to visit and great food!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cats or dogs?&lt;/em&gt; I’m not really an animal person.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Favorite artist?&lt;/em&gt; The photographer Annie Leibovitz.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best thing that happened this month?&lt;/em&gt; Getting to play Maria in the musical ‘West Side Story’.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best thing that happened ever?&lt;/em&gt; The invention of food delivery services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Facebook or Instagram?&lt;/em&gt; Instagram.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Favorite holiday?&lt;/em&gt; Thanksgiving.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Biggest surprise you’ve ever had?&lt;/em&gt; A surprise party before I left England.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you could pick one historical figure to have coffee with, whom would you pick?&lt;/em&gt; Tea with Margaret Thatcher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best gift you ever received?&lt;/em&gt; Being brought ice cream (by P) when all I could eat was cold liquids after I had my wisdom teeth out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Favorite country you visited?&lt;/em&gt; Greece.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Number one goal in life?&lt;/em&gt; To find my name on a fridge magnet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Movie you laughed the hardest through?&lt;/em&gt; No question, Bridesmaids.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best thing about living in Rome?&lt;/em&gt; Pompi tiramisu.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you could switch places with someone for a day, who would it be?&lt;/em&gt; I’d swap with someone who is extremely tall. See what the view is like!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dream job?&lt;/em&gt;  If only there was such job as an “Official Mattress Tester”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Who should everyone be following right now?&lt;/em&gt; Anna Kendrick.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Benches of an Author</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/03/benches-of-an-author"/>
   <updated>2015-03-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/03/benches-of-an-author</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;“La panchina è un luogo di sosta, un’utopia realizzata. E’ vacanza a portata di mano. Sulle panchine si contempla lo spettacolo del mondo, si guarda senza essere visti e ci si dà il tempo di perdere il tempo, come leggere un romanzo.”
&lt;cite&gt;Beppe Sebaste, da “Panchine. Come uscire dal mondo senza uscirne”&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The bench is a resting place, a realized utopia. It is a vacation at hand. On benches we contemplate the spectacle of the world, you look without being seen, and it gives us the time to lose time, like reading a novel.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In February, the Italian author, poet and journalist for the newspapers &lt;em&gt;L’Unità and La Repubblica&lt;/em&gt;, Beppe Sebaste, visited and honored Italian Literature 1 and IB Italian Literature HL students by discussing and answering questions on his esteemed novel, &lt;em&gt;Panchine. Come uscire dal mondo senza uscirne. (Benches. How to escape from the world without leaving it)&lt;/em&gt;. Marymount was honored to meet guest speaker, Sebaste, at this event, which was organized by Ms. Iorio. Sebaste, a secluded and diligent writer who spends most of his time writing, rarely leaves his office, except when he walks through the parks of Rome. Social events are not part of Sebaste’s routine, so when he did arrive at Marymount and saw the enquiring students, and “Il Progetto Panchine” (the bench project) that Ms. Iorio and her students had organized in the Bosco di Calvino near the Little Free Library, Sebaste shed a few tears from the impact his novel had on the young literature scholars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his novel, Sebaste talks about the role of benches in society, literature, history, science etc. According to Sebaste, benches are places where “we contemplate the spectacle of the world, you look without being seen, and it gives us the time to lose time.” For the author, sitting on a bench is escaping reality while still being present in it. The world stops for you while sitting on a bench and permits you to observe your surroundings while not being observed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While visiting the Little Free Library, Italian Literature students and Ms. Iorio noticed that there was something missing from that area created about two years ago, where people can borrow and donate books. The missing element was both essential and yet hidden: benches. There was no “formal” place to sit and read the books. Immediately, the “Progetto Panchine”, a plan to construct benches for the Little Free Library, began. The day that Sebaste arrived at Marymount, the project was inaugurated. Thanks to a benevolent benefactor who donated pellet to the Progetto Panchine, it was possible to create these benches that accommodate the readers of the Little Free Library. The Italian Literature students would like to thank Beppe Sebaste for inspiring them and prompting this improvement to the Little Free Library project.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>How Kanye West Became a Verb</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/03/how-kanye-west-became-a-verb"/>
   <updated>2015-03-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/03/how-kanye-west-became-a-verb</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Everyone remembers the 2009 VMA Awards as they would remember an extremely bad birthday party. Kanye West’s brazen and aggressive interruption of Taylor Swift’s speech, which merited national attention, inspired an insurmountable amount of memes, and ruined his already iffy reputation. Taylor Swift even “swifted” Kanye by writing a song about the incident (yes, she too is regarded as a verb in her own right.) In short, to “Kanye” is a pop culture reference that is widely alluded to by all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just last month, Beyoncé lost “Album of the Year” at the Grammy’s to Beck (who?) and Kanye West decided it would be neat if he recreated his stunt by “jokingly” starting up the stage to interrupt Beck’s speech and then cheekily retreading. His attempt at a ‘meta’ moment doesn’t read as tongue-in-cheek as he hoped it would. Once again, he trampled on yet another respected artist’s glory because he felt as though the world was dying for his opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This type of asinine and immature behavior has become expected from West. When a celebrity repeats an action enough times, that action takes over their brand. They become a caricature of that action and their every move is scrutinized with that action in mind. And with that, they are canonized into the “verb hall of fame”: they become living, breathing grammatical devices that can morph from the present participle to the past participle and provide plenty of context to a sentence. If someone were described as having “Kanyed” a situation, you would immediately understand the unpleasant connotation: the definition has been programmed into our brains by the insane amount of discussion his actions have instigated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a fascinating dynamic, one that can only occur in the realms of stardom. That is why celebrities should, nay, must be careful of how they present themselves to the world. They have power, sure, but the world has the even greater power to turn their name against them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The “Verb Hall of Fame”&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taylor Swift&lt;/strong&gt; (v.) to air all of your dirty laundry via means of artistic expression, may that be a song, a script or an angry Facebook status.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chris Brown&lt;/strong&gt; (v.) to be extremely violent or hostile towards women: the antithesis of feminism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Britney Spears&lt;/strong&gt; (v.) to spiral out of control in a careless and horrifying manner. Synonyms: Lindsey Lohan, Jessica Simpson.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oprah Winfrey&lt;/strong&gt; (v.) to hide lavish presents under people’s seats Antonym: Dr. Phil.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Alexis Tspiras</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/03/alexis-tspiras"/>
   <updated>2015-03-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/03/alexis-tspiras</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There is so much wrong with Alexis Tspiras and Syriza that I’m afraid that this article won’t be able to make you, the reader, understand why Tspiras and his radical left-wing party, Syriza, is the straw that will break Greece’s back and consequentially worsen the European Union (EU) in its entirety. Alas I’ll do my best to present an argument which will dismantle an already broken political party and hopefully knock some sense in those who still hold on to the idea that any form of political radicalism, whether it’s right-wing or left-wing, will “save” the people from the austerity policies that are slowly suffocating the EU.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past decade Greece has seen so many economic ordeals that its debt crisis alone encapsulates how the EU’s, or rather, how Angela Merkel’s austerity policies have sent the whole of Europe into an economic recession that is so counter-productive that it’s almost as if every EU nation had lost a major war which reduced its economy to something similar to post WWI Germany. Seriously. Greece has suffered particularly from this global economic crisis, to the point which since the early 90’s it has been losing money, its people have become poorer and it has been home to ridiculous levels of corruption and tax evasion. Tspiras’ political success is a product of this colossal economic failure because, like most current politicians love to do,  he has, since the start of his political campaign, been pointing his finger at Germany, the EU, Austerity and basically anything that participated the economic, diplomatic and social collapse of Greece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, why is Tspiras so detrimental to Greece? First off, he is inconsistent and arguably hypocritical as shown from the fact that the first action he and Syriza undertook after winning the general elections was to form a coalition for parliamentary majority with A.N.E.L, the Greek right-wing independent party, which isn’t exactly the ideal candidate for a coalition with a RADICAL LEFT-WING PARTY. Secondly, he is already panicking and making stupid decisions. Tspiras has been in power for little more that two months and in this little time he has already made the very smart choice of demanding that Germany pay around €11 billion of reparations for the occupation of Greece by hand of the Nazi’s in WWII. Germany had the decency to limit their response to this ridiculous proposal to a mere “nein”, but if Tspiras were looking for a way to butcher Greece’s already weak relations with Europe and to make a fool out of himself, he found what’s inarguably the best way to do so. Last but not least he has promised so many overly ambitious goals to the Greek people that it’s gone to the point in which it’s become all very comical. He wants to leave the European Union, leave the Euro, stop austerity, fix Greece’s economy, renegotiate the €240bn + Greek debt to Europe, save the world from an alien invasion, colonize the moon and become God. Okay, he did not quite say the first three, but you get the idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tspiras isn’t the PM Greece needs nor deserves. Whether it will all go downhill from here is debatable but out of all the people that the Greek could have elected I’m quite sure he wasn’t the one they should have even considered.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Net Neutrality: The Little-Known Protector of Digital Citizens</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/03/net-neutrality-the-little-known-protector-of-digital-citizens"/>
   <updated>2015-03-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/03/net-neutrality-the-little-known-protector-of-digital-citizens</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Whether browsing Facebook, researching, or trolling the depths of the net, the Internet has become nearly inseparable from our daily lives. One of the great things about the Internet is net neutrality: the equal treatment of all data on the Internet by governments and Internet service providers (ISPs). This means that internet providers like Telecom Italia and Wind cannot force users to pay extra to use websites like Google, Facebook, or Wikipedia. They also can’t slow down Internet speeds for specific websites or applications. On top of protecting consumers from exorbitant prices, net neutrality helps protect the very essence of free Internet, a medium that allows everyone to create and post anything for all to see. Without net neutrality, smaller websites would most likely go out of business, not being able to pay ISP’s extra money to have their content sent out to the public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While net neutrality may seem like an obvious and integral aspect of the Internet, most of the public don’t even realize what it is. Now, this wouldn’t be such an issue if most governments protected it. However, around the world, many governments haven’t set specific rules to protect net neutrality, most of them not having altered their laws since the popularization of the Internet. In fact, the United States of America’s Federal Communications Commission (FCC), that governs communications by radio, television, wire, satellite, and cable, only recently, on the 26th of February 2015, passed laws protecting net neutrality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The European Union however has yet to come to a ruling on net neutrality, with many member states having conflicting opinions on the topic. Italy, along with Spain and others, follow an anti-net neutrality stand, aiming to appease their telecommunications market. This was evident from last terms President of the Council of the European Union, Matteo Renzi, who attempted to limit the definition of net neutrality throughout the EU. This was met with opposition from many parties, in particular members of the European Digital Rights group, claiming Renzi was “backpedaling on meaningful net neutrality protections.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With discussions still being held amongst the European Union, telecommunications companies are spending inordinate amounts of money lobbying for countries to abolish or nullify these rules, and some countries are listening. Without citizens to fight for net neutrality, the future of the Internet will most likely become one of increased prices, stifled innovation and lackluster content. We hope that like the U.S, Europe will hear their citizens and follow in suit to protect us digital citizens.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Piracy and the Internet: Reaching Common Ownership</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/03/piracy-and-the-internet-reaching-common-ownership"/>
   <updated>2015-03-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/03/piracy-and-the-internet-reaching-common-ownership</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Who pays to download music? I do not, I torrent it. Who pays to watch a movie? I do so very rarely because I prefer free internet streaming to buying DVDs. In this age of mass globalization and universal digitalization of the media, we still have a very antiquated mentality on the concept of property, especially on intellectual property. Nowadays, intellectual property is immaterial and fundamentally impossible to protect; if your work merits attention, it probably already is available to download for free on some site. The Internet, and this is a fact, is the homeland of piracy, yet the word ‘piracy’ is too archaic to describe the phenomenon of global ownership that is being driven by the global network. What meaning do the concepts of property and of theft itself have when I can download on my computer in my room a movie, that was produced in a different country far from Italy, without ever making contact with the creators? Stuck in the mentality of “I made that, therefore I have the right to want money for it,” creators seethe with impotent anger at torrenting, streaming, and free download sites. They would do their over-taxed minds, their over-worked lawyers, and us a favor if they just could forget all about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sharing is the foundation of the Internet. The Internet has made the common ownership of any sort of intellectual property that can be digitalized possible. Even now, Internet common ownership might be expanding even more with the advent of 3D printers, which will have enormous repercussions on labor. The capitalist notion of royalties and of digital rights management is rapidly and beautifully falling apart, being slowly replaced by a digital common ownership that is reminiscent of an ideology that was never really quite well-understood. Now, let us for a moment assume that suddenly corporations and governments understood the futility of their inept and dreadfully authoritarian attempts to ‘protect’ intellectual property and that they suddenly decided to legalize all forms of what is nowadays called ‘digital privacy’. In this hypothetical reality, creators of digital commodities would have two choices: either stop producing or produce even more. In the first case, humanity would quickly become a dull place, and probably about half of the world’s population would be working in professions they hate but had to adopt because they liked money more than their art. In the second case instead, property as a means of building capital, at least in the digital world, would be completely abolished but art and digital products would thrive because there would be a much greater participation of people who might not have been able to access the products before the free Internet. The digital world would flourish, open source software would be a normal thing, not that awfully communist sounding thing some developers adopt for reasons that seem obscure to the layman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now this is all good and well, but how would half of the world’s population eat without royalties? To the wannabe artist this sounds like a very serious catch (as if Van Gogh or Mozart had been millionaires), yet the problem is immaterial. Putting aside the plethora of studies that show that empirically Internet sharing has not disincentivized anyone to stop doing anything nor has it decreased the size of any industry (whether it be music or film or architecture software), let us consider the human factor. Would you still go to concerts if you could access all the music in the world? I think I still would. Would you support your favorite software designer’s company if you had money to spare? I think I would. Accepting the Internet’s ‘pirate’ nature would remove the middle-man (always an awkward presence that always inspires distrust) and put the focus on the product itself, not on the number of billboards it has on Corso Francia.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Fake Brat: Part IV</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/02/fake-brat-part-iv"/>
   <updated>2015-02-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/02/fake-brat-part-iv</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Katelyn and I trotted up to apartment 6B where the sound of muffled voices and loud music was coming from. A few seconds before Katelyn was about to ring the doorbell, my phone started to ring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Ugh, just a second. It’s my parents, if I don’t answer now they won’t stop calling me all night long.” I told Katelyn as I answered the phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I could even put the phone up to my ear, the screeching sound of my mothers voice flew through the speakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Where the heck are you?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m fine thanks for asking,” I sighed, “I’m at a friend’s house.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Do you think after what you did at the gala I will allow you to just wonder off like that?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nothing happened mother! I just fell on a guy, that’s it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nothing happened?!” She asked me, her voice slowly rising in volume to match her obvious anger. “You embarrassed both me and your father and just left the party! That’s what happened.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the sudden there was a low voice talking to my mother in the background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Is that her?” My father asked. My mother must have nodded her head and given him the phone because next thing I knew, my father was shouting at me just like my mother had done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You are in so much trouble young lady!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh I’m sorry, is your secretary too busy that you actually noticed something going on in your family.” I asked him my anger growing just as much as theirs. “You know what, do whatever you want, I’ll see you later.” I hanged up before either of them could say anything else. I turned back around to face Katelyn and gave her a small nod. She replied with a warm smile before ringing the doorbell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey Joe!” Katelyn shouted as Joe opened the door to his apartment. He didn’t change at all since the last time we saw him. He was still the same thin, tall guy with dark hair and a matching beard. I mean, if  you can even call two hairs on his chin a beard. We told him it looked ridiculous but he wouldn’t listen claiming that it made him more of a “man.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hey ladies,” Joe replied once he saw it was us. “Dressed a bit formal for my party?” He asked examining our long gowns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You are throwing a party and didn’t think of inviting us? Consider me offended!” Katelyn replied ignoring his question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe shrugged, “I knew you two would be coming whether I was inviting you or not so there wasn’t really any need to.” He opened the door wider allowing us to walk passed him and into the apartment. Joe, being a sophomore at university, had a small apartment all to himself meaning that every now and then he would allow himself the pleasure of throwing a party. The apartment wasn’t luxurious and opulent like the things I was used to, but that is why I loved coming here so much. Unlike the other parties Joe threw, there wasn’t such a large crowd of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You wouldn’t believe what Jennifer did at her parent’s friend’s gala just about an hour ago.” Katelyn said not waiting a minute longer to share my embarrassing moment with our friend. After I fell on the new kid in front of everyone Katelyn pulled me away from the crowd. Together we sneaked out the back entrance of the hotel and caught a taxi so that we could come here. We both knew better than to stick around the gala after the stunt I had just pulled off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Let me guess, she fell on some handsome blonde hair, green eyed guy in front of everyone.” Joe replied while dropping down to sit on his old sofa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah… How did you know?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Its already all over those stupid gossip sites.” He replied pulling out his phone. “Jennifer Moorse throws herself on her new mysterious guy at the Clarkson’s gala at the Royal Hotel.” Joe read off one of the sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What?!” I snatched the phone out of his hands. I scroll down the page only to see that he was telling the truth. They were actually claiming that I “purposely threw” myself on him! It couldn’t get any more embarrassing than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Who cares about what these stupid sites say.” Joe reassured me once he saw my flushed face. He took his phone back and pocketed it in his jeans. “Just relax and have some fun.” I replied with a nod and allowed Katelyn to drag me off to the kitchen so we could get something to drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hours passed and so did the memory of the gala. We danced and laughed along the beat of the music. The room was hot and sticky, filled with the warmth of too many human bodies in a closed place. My mind was fuzzy, my sight was blurry and my skin was numb. I had lost Katelyn a few minutes after we had started dancing and was now talking to a girl about a book we had both read. Slowly losing interest in the subject I looked around the foggy room. There was one guy sitting on the old sofa watching television, but he seemed indecisive of what he wanted to watch as he continued to flip through the channels.  A group of his friends called his name distracting him from the television that was now left on the News. All of the sudden I felt my feet move away from the girl in the middle of her discussion and towards the television as a picture of my parents appeared near the reporter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Turn it up…” I told the guy sitting on the old sofa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What?” The guy asked me not really paying attention to what I had said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I said turn it up!” I shouted at the guy, getting annoyed that he was being so slow. Startled by my sudden aggression he turned the volume up. The whole room seemed to be silenced, the only thing I could hear was the reporter’s annoyingly perfect voice, “ Jacobe Moorse and Cassandra Moorse instantly dead in a car accident seconds after their exit from the Royal Hotel…”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To be continued…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Fake Brat: Part III</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/01/fake-brat-part-iii"/>
   <updated>2015-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2015/01/fake-brat-part-iii</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The limousine stopped in front of the luxurious hotel. As the chauffeur opened the door for us, we were blinded by the flash of the multiple cameras. My dad, wanting to prove his masculinity, was the first to step out of the car. He helped out my mother, who clutched on his side as she slid out the car elegantly. Together, with fake smiles plastered on their faces, they walked down the carpet and towards the double door entrance. Sometimes stopping to pose for the paparazzi, so that their loving couple image would be pictured and later on advertised to the world. If only they knew how truly loving they were towards each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Katelyn and I were next. Our hair was brushed and burned to perfection while our faces were painted on like canvasses. Unlike my parents, we never stopped to pose. We walked, well more like cantered, down the carpet, with our head held high as we ignored the shouts from the reporters and paparazzi calling for us to give them a chance for a good photo and even a word or two. I could see the different people being stopped to pose and interviewed, as I continued my long walk towards the entrance. Some looked happy while others looked smug. But one group stood out more than others: two teenage girls, just a few years younger than us. They were being interviewed by a famous reporter, which I had forgotten the name. Didn’t really matter, each one of them were the same at the end. Telling you to be yourself but really wanting you to be the person that sells. The teenage girls look scared and excited at the same time. They must be newbies. You could tell by how one of them, who looked flustered and nervous, was playing with her hair. A big no-no in this world. It made her posture crooked and her personality look weak. Or at least that is what the other people walking down this carpet would say. I, on the other hand, think it’s cute. It made her look almost innocent. An adjective never used among people with fame or power. It wasn’t like they weren’t nice people, some were actually decent. It’s just that none of us could actually permit to be seen as innocent. The media would eat you alive, while your rivals would squash you without mercy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Katelyn and I finally reached the doors that shielded us away from the blinding light. Once in, they took us in this large opulent room, with large chandeliers and expensive paintings. Everything seemed so forced. As if the hosts had to show off their wealth by putting the most luxuries things they owned in the room. We walked off to our assigned table and sat down in sighed unison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, this is going to be fun.” Katelyn said, sarcasm pouring from every word. I laughed in agreement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Don’t worry about it, we’ll stay here just for about an hour, then sneak out, grab a taxi and head at Joe’s. Sounds cool?” I asked her, observing my father who was talking business with his friends while his hand lay on the very low back of his “secretary”, Ashley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sounds like our typical Friday night.” She replied as she gave me a humorous smile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I nodded in agreement, a similar smile sneaking up on my lips. “I’m going to get something to drink, want anything?” Katelyn shook her head as she continued to observe the people around the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked around, pushing through crowds of people as I searched for even a sneak peek of the bar. I tried to avoid my parents or any of their acquaintances not being in the mood to have any formal chit-chat about business or how I should date one of their sons. However, I had no such luck as my mum’s eyes met mine. She called for my name, but, acting as if I hadn’t seen or heard her, I span around and walked away only to crash into someone. All the sudden everything was blurry and I could hear the wind rushing by my ear, until I stopped moving and heard a low grunt come from underneath me. I had realized too late that I had fell on top of someone. And not just anyone, but on the owner of those familiar beautiful green eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m so s-sorry.” I stuttered as I continued to stare into his captivating eyes. I still couldn’t believe I just fell on top of the new kid from my school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh, it’s fine. I’m use to having girls fall for me.” He replied nonchalant, a smirk forming on his lips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I laughed. “Excuse me? I didn’t fall for you, it was a mere accident! I’m not even attracted to you.” I snapped back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Really?” He asked. “Then why are you still laying on me?” His smirk grew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mouth was snap shut as I noticed that what he had said was true. I could feel the blood being drawn to my face, as a strong blush formed. I quickly pulled away, petting my dress down. I turned away from him, only to notice that we had gathered a crowd that included both Katelyn and my parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was never going to hear the end of this from neither of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To be continued…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Fake Brat: Part II</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2014/12/fake-brat-part-ii"/>
   <updated>2014-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2014/12/fake-brat-part-ii</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The day flew by without trouble. I hadn’t seen the new guy since biology class, and apart from catching him staring at me a few times, we still hadn’t properly conversed. Katelyn and I were walking out of the school and towards my ride when a young girl bumped into me. The girl, who couldn’t have been older than fifteen, fell to floor along with her multiple papers that were now scattered. I started to bend down to help her, but before I could even touch one piece of paper she looked up at me with fear written all over her face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I-I’m so sorry Jennifer Moorse, I didn’t m-mean to disturb you, or to talk to you, or even touch you.” She quickly picked up all the pieces of papers and pulled herself up. “It will never happen again p-promised. I’m so s-sorry!” She turned around and ran away. I sighed as I watched her jolt away. This kind of behavior wouldn’t disturb me if a freshman would act like this around every senior, but I knew that they only acted like this with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Katelyn didn’t comment but silently followed me as I started walking again towards my ride. I noticed that most of the students were cautiously watching my every move, expecting me to have some kind of drama queen explosion about having a “nobody” interact with me. The truth is, even if I did help out that girl the way I wanted to, they would have analyzed that kind action as a rich girl just wanting to get some attention from others. Whatever I did, they would always find a way to paint me as a spoiled rich kid. And there wasn’t much I could do to fight that sort of prejudice, and so I continued walking a black Bentley: my ride. Of course along with such an expensive car came a driver. I mean, Why learn how to drive when you can buy a driver or at least that’s what my mom says. Katelyn and I slided into the car and Mark, my driver, started the engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hi Mark,” Katelyn and me said unison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Good afternoon Ms. Moorse, Ms. Janson.” Mark replied. “Where to?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Home, please.” Mark nodded and pulled the car out the parking lot of the school. “And Mark?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes Miss.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Don’t call us from our surnames, we are all friends in here.” I told him for the hundredth time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mark laughed, “Ok Jennifer.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So-o…” Katelyn said breaking the comfortable silent. “Want to talk about what just happened five minutes ago?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I rolled my eyes. “There isn’t much to talk about. It’s the same thing every time. They are scared of me, or at least of what I can do.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Katelyn nodded in agreement. “I was just shocked she actually remembered your name instead of only your surname.” We laughed about it for a few seconds until we fell back into a comfortable silence accompanied by radio’s music in the background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few minutes later we arrived to my bombastic and exaggeratedly large house. I thanked Mark for taking us home and walked through the two huge white doors that were opened by our butler, Jason.  I was about to thank him when my, ever so lovely, mother popped out of nowhere and interrupt me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh sweetheart! Thank God you’re home. I called your hairdresser and she’s waiting for you in your room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Meredith? Why is she here?” I asked her curiously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well to do your hair for tonight’s party silly. I know it’s a last minute thing but the Clarkson’s are throwing an extremely important party at the Royal Hotel.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I groaned. “Another party? Can’t I stay home for just one Friday night?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Absolutely not!” She replied as if I had asked the most offensive thing in the world. “You, along with this family, have an image to uphold!” She looked at Katelyn that was standing next to me silently. “ You can bring your friend, uh-h-h, Katherine right?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Katelyn mum! She’s been my best friend since we were five!” I said angrily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sure… Why you’re at it, why don’t you call that handsome friend Jackson?” She answered not really caring about Katelyn, but about my pretentious ex-boyfriend, who she wanted me to marry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Because we broke up about a week ago, and also because he’s a dou-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Cassandra?” My dad walked in calling for my mom, interrupting me. “Did you see my phone? I wanted to call the secretary.” As he stood in front of us he noticed me only later. “Oh Honey, sorry hadn’t seen you there.” He leaned to give me a kiss on the cheek but I moved out of his reach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’re secretary?” I asked him suspiciously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah, her name is Ashley, she used to be a student at your school last year.” He told me, acting as if we both didn’t know who she really was; his mistress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You’re taking her to the party?” I asked shocked. Why was he bringing her to such an important event with all his and my mother’s friends? Wasn’t he afraid of being caught?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yes I need her for some work business.” He said nonchalant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“For work or for you?” I challenged him. He gave me a stern look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As tension grew in the air, I walked away from my parents with Katelyn by my side, silently as always.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To be continued…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Fake Brat: Part I</title>
   <link href="http://theroyalliar.github.io/2014/11/fake-brat-part-i"/>
   <updated>2014-11-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://theroyalliar.github.io/2014/11/fake-brat-part-i</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Money, one of the only things I extremely hated yet needed it to survive. It built up my life but, at the same time, ruined it. It allowed me to go to any school I wanted, choose whatever job I wanted, travel where ever I wanted and get anything I wanted. But it also made me insecure, and doubt my friends’ true intentions; making me often lonely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In today’s society money was not anymore just a form of survival, but it also determined where you stood in society, or as I like to call it, “humanity’s food chain”. If you were wealthy you automatically had power over others less fortunate than you. I never truly understood the reason, but it seemed to be the primary rule of life. And I, being the daughter of Jacobe Moorse; a well known, wealthy businessman, know all about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People automatically presumed I was a spoiled, fake and heartless brat. And I gave them no reason to believe other wise.  I couldn’t be bothered to prove them wrong, and acted exactly like society and the press wanted me to act. I think there is only one person in my life that actually knows who the real me is, and that is my best friend Katelyn. Not even my parents knew what was really going on in my life. My father was too busy cheating on my mother with a former student at my school; she graduated last year from high school. I had caught them “cuddling” two years ago, while I was still a sophomore and she was one of my best friends, in my room. My father, after I screamed and ran out of the room from the horror, came after me and convinced me to not tell my mother anything. In all honesty there wasn’t much convincing needed, as I wouldn’t want to be the one giving her the heartbreaking news. Plus she was too deep into society to care about anything else but which dress to wear at which party. So yeah, my parents were too busy with their own lives to even notice that their own daughter disappeared for a whole two weeks last year. But Katelyn. Oh Katelyn. There hasn’t past been a moment in my life where Katelyn wasn’t there for me. I mean, it would be an insult towards her to even call her a friend instead of a sister.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Earth to Jenna!” Katelyn’s hand waved in front of my face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Huh?!” I whipped my face to hers and blinked. “What did I miss?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The new student’s introduction. He’s quite a looker, but he also has that kind of bad-boy vibe, which means all the girls are going to be drooling over him.” She babbled on while sketching in her notebook.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New student? What was she talking about? I looked around the dull grey laboratory only to see a blond male around my age standing next to the teacher’s desk. The boy’s green eyes met mine and we just stared at each other for a few seconds. His lips formed a perfect smirked right before he ripped his eyes off me and turned his attention back to the old teacher. I knew, right there and then that, just like in any cliché teenage story, this boy wasn’t going to be anything but trouble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To be continued…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
